<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articlearchive>
    <articles>
        <article>
            <id>92</id>
            <title>Attorney General Pam Bondi, followed by Federal Bureau of Investigation Director Kash Patel and U.S. Attorney for the District of Columbia Jeanine Pirro arrive for a press briefing in the James S. Brady Press Briefing Room at the White House on Aug. 11, 2025.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/28/bondi-patel-to-testify-before-congress-amid-epstein-fallout-00534353</link>
            <description>The attorney general and FBI director are expected to face fierce questioning by Democrats and some Republicans over the DOJ’s handling of the Jeffrey Epstein case.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-28T13:07:22</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>5</id>
                <name>Meredith</name>
                <surname>Lee</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\33de43ef-7f14-4d62-a55c-937194e0b262.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Two top Justice Department officials are expected to testify before the House Judiciary Committee in the coming weeks amid fallout over the administration's handling of the Jeffrey Epstein case, according to two people granted anonymity to share scheduling information not yet public.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;FBI director Kash Patel is set to give testimony Sept. 17, with attorney general Pam Bondi on tap to appear Oct. 9. Both have been invited as part of the Judiciary Committee’s general oversight work, and each will have an opportunity to outline some of the pieces of a crime bill President Donald Trump wants Hill Republicans to produce in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But the hearings will likely focus most heavily on how the DOJ has maneuvered around the release of files related to the late, convicted sex offender.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Senior Republicans have continued over the August recess to press the Trump administration to unseal more Epstein documents after a mutiny over their release caused chaos in the GOP-controlled House, running the chamber aground before lawmakers left town early in late July.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;DOJ started transmitting some of the so-called Epstein files last week in compliance with a subpoena from the House Oversight and Government Reform Committee. And Alex Acosta, President Donald Trump’s former labor secretary who singed off on Epstein’s previous plea deal as a then-U.S. attorney in Florida, will separately sit for a transcribed interview with the Oversight panel Sept. 19.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;However, lawmakers otherwise have so far received scant new information during the month-long district work period, with members of both parties promising to continue to press the issue when the House is set to return to session next week.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Bondi has, in particular, &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/07/24/pam-bondi-jeffrey-epstein-files-00475897" target="_blank"&gt;been the subject&lt;/a&gt; of Republican consternation over allegedly withholding documents she at one point promised to reveal.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>93</id>
            <title>Kennedy, seen at a Capitol roundtable discussion event in July, has not appeared before a Senate committee since May.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/28/robert-kennedy-senate-hearing-cdc-00533906</link>
            <description>The Finance Committee hearing was in the works before Wednesday’s CDC shakeup.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-28T11:13:27</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>6</id>
                <name>Jordain</name>
                <surname>Carney</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\8dd5c44b-b730-4574-9962-35629670a01a.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Senators will soon get a chance to question Health and Human Services Secretary Robert F. Kennedy Jr. about Wednesday’s sudden shakeup at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Kennedy will testify before the Senate Finance Committee on Sept. 4, two people granted anonymity to describe the plans first told POLITICO Thursday. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Finance Chair Mike Crapo (R-Idaho) said in a subsequent statement confirming the hearing that Kennedy would speak before the panel on President Donald Trump's health care agenda.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Kennedy has placed addressing the underlying causes of chronic diseases at the forefront of this Administration’s health care agenda,” Crapo said. “I look forward to learning more about the Department of Health and Human Services’ Make America Healthy Again actions to date and plans moving forward.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Kennedy’s appearance before the Finance panel was in the works before the White House fired CDC Director Susan Monarez, who is now challenging her ouster. Three &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/27/hhs-monarez-no-longer-director-of-cdc-00532488" target="_blank"&gt;top CDC leaders resigned&lt;/a&gt; minutes after news of Monarez’s ouster broke.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Numerous Democrats have sharply criticized the CDC moves, including calling for a congressional investigation or for Kennedy to be fired. Sen. Jon Ossoff of Georgia, where the agency is based, said “putting a quack like Bobby Kennedy in charge of public health was a grave error” and that the Trump administration’s “extremism and incompetence are putting lives at risk.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Sen. Ron Wyden of Oregon, the top Democrat on the Finance Committee, sent a letter to Kennedy Thursday reminding him of unanswered requests for information sent by members of the panel this year.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"Your tenure as Secretary thus far has been the most opaque and secretive of any federal agency in living memory. This hearing represents an opportunity to correct course," Wyden wrote.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The hearing will be senators’ first opportunity to question Kennedy face-to-face since May, when he appeared separately before the Senate HELP and Appropriations committees to discuss his department’s fiscal 2026 budget request.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Sen. Bill Cassidy (R-La.), who chairs the HELP Committee and is also a member of the Finance panel, &lt;a href="https://x.com/SenBillCassidy/status/1960895774079799344" target="_blank"&gt;said Wednesday night&lt;/a&gt; that “these high profile departures will require oversight” by his committee.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Kennedy defended the CDC shakeup during a Fox News interview Thursday. Though he declined to talk about “personnel issues,” he added that the “agency is in trouble, and we need to fix it … and it may be that some people should not be working there anymore.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>94</id>
            <title>Mark Teixeira of the New York Yankees follows through as he hits an RBI single to center field to score Jacoby Ellsbury during the eighth inning of a game against the Tampa Bay Rays on July 29, 2016, at Tropicana Field in St. Petersburg, Florida.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/28/mark-teixeira-mlb-congress-00533795</link>
            <description>Teixeira was a superstar on the diamond, going yard 409 times in a career saw him play for four big league outfits, including the Texas Rangers and New York Yankees.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-28T11:11:00</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>7</id>
                <name>Gregory</name>
                <surname>Svirnovskiy</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\26bb67c2-9d66-41b8-b3c0-a3db660eec02.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Baseball star Mark Teixeira launched a campaign to fill an open Texas House seat Thursday, the latest celebrity athlete to dive into politics.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Teixeira is running as a Republican in a safe red seat being vacated by GOP Rep. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/3265" data-person-id="3265"&gt;Chip Roy&lt;/a&gt;. And he’s already appealing to President Donald Trump in search of a home run on the campaign trail.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“As a lifelong conservative who loves this country, I’m running for Congress to fight for the principles that make Texas and America great,” &lt;a href="https://x.com/teixeiramark25/status/1961080787584897174" target="_blank"&gt;he wrote in a post on X&lt;/a&gt;. “It takes teamwork to win — I’m ready to help defend President Trump’s America First agenda, Texas families, and individual liberty.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Teixeira was a superstar on the diamond, &lt;a href="https://www.mlb.com/player/mark-teixeira-407893" target="_blank"&gt;going yard 409 times in a career&lt;/a&gt; that spanned 14 seasons and saw him play for four big league outfits, including the Texas Rangers and New York Yankees. He last played in the 2016 season.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;He &lt;a href="https://www.mlb.com/news/mark-teixeira-was-yankees-missing-link-in-2009" target="_blank"&gt;reached baseball immortality&lt;/a&gt; when the Yankees won the World Series in 2009. He was included on the 2022 Hall of Fame ballot but failed to get enough votes from sportswriters to either get elected to the Hall or return to the ballot in future years.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Should he win the seat, he could be a major boon for Republicans in the Congressional Baseball Game, the annual charity event that pits Democrats against Republicans. The GOP has dominated the game in recent years, a gap that a former major leaguer would likely only widen.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Teixeira is leaning into his baseball bona fides.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“In Congress, he’ll bring the same grit, preparation, and competitive spirit that made him a champion in Major League Baseball to fight for Texas—and win,” &lt;a href="https://teixeiraforcongress.com/" target="_blank"&gt;reads his campaign website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Roy, a Freedom Caucus member who has served in the House since 2019, is leaving Congress to &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/21/chip-roy-texas-attorney-general-run-00517391" target="_blank"&gt;run for the Texas attorney general post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>95</id>
            <title>President Donald Trump speaks during a cabinet meeting at the White House in Washington on Aug. 26, 2025.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/27/trump-comprehensive-crime-bill-dc-00531202</link>
            <description>The president said Wednesday there would be “more to follow” amid preliminary talks on Capitol Hill.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-27T14:46:19</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>5</id>
                <name>Meredith</name>
                <surname>Lee</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\2d47d7c3-c422-4956-b919-a6c4481e52c6.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump is envisioning a sweeping crime bill and billions of dollars in new funding for the nation’s capital. His Republican allies in Congress are largely in the dark on the details.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Multiple times this month, Trump has said he’s working on crime legislation with GOP congressional leaders. His latest comment came early Wednesday morning when he posted on Truth Social that he is working with Speaker Mike Johnson, Senate Majority Leader John Thune and other Republican lawmakers on a “Comprehensive Crime Bill” with “more to follow.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;There have been some early conversations between White House officials and House GOP leadership aides about legislation related to Trump’s public-safety crackdown in Washington as well as certain other crime provisions.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But Trump’s latest comments have puzzled Republicans, including members of leadership and key congressional committees, who don’t know what “comprehensive” measure the president is talking about, according to seven Republicans granted anonymity to speak candidly.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump, who speaks frequently with Johnson, discussed the president’s Washington crime campaign with the speaker on a call Tuesday morning, including extending his current temporary control over the D.C. police, according to two other people granted anonymity to describe the private conversation. Johnson was supportive of an extension, they said.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The House Oversight Committee, which has jurisdiction over D.C. issues, is already planning to &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/11/dc-crime-congress-house-gop-00504032" target="_blank"&gt;advance a slate of bills&lt;/a&gt; in September, spanning efforts to crack down on juvenile crime in Washington, overhaul the city’s education system and unwind certain policing policies enacted by the D.C. Council. But it’s the Judiciary Committee that would have to advance any crime-related bills that are national in scope.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump’s request to extend his 30-day D.C. police takeover is adding a wrinkle to the House GOP’s plans, since his authority is set to expire Sept. 9 — just one week after lawmakers return to Washington. Republican leaders will need to advance it quickly — likely in a resolution they will put directly on the floor — leaving a broader package for later.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Even if the House quickly passes the extension, its fate in the Senate is uncertain. Trump said during a marathon Cabinet meeting Tuesday that he’s planning to speak with Thune about the matter. But because of the chamber’s filibuster rule, Republicans can’t act alone to approve the measure, and Senate Democrats have signaled they’ll block any attempt to do so.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Still, Republicans are eager to force Democrats into tough votes on crime, which they see as &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2025/08/26/trump-crime-democrats-midterms-00523437" target="_blank"&gt;advantageous political ground&lt;/a&gt; — especially with House GOP leaders facing ongoing headaches over the Jeffrey Epstein case and the administration’s handling of it.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Republicans are also still waiting on details on what Trump has described as a $2 billion bill to “beautify” Washington. Republican Sens. Lindsey Graham of South Carolina and Katie Britt of Alabama are taking the lead on the D.C. funding bill, and Trump spoke with Graham, who is currently traveling overseas, about the president’s plan for the capital city earlier this month.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I’m going to try to find him the money to repave the roads, take the graffiti off the building, refurbish the parks and give homeless people some place to go other than a tent,” Graham said at a South Carolina event last week.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;D.C. Mayor Muriel Bowser said at a news conference Wednesday that she, too, was sketchy on the details of what Trump is proposing with the federal funding infusion. But she said “we will be supportive of the president's $2 billion request to improve infrastructure, especially federal infrastructure, in the District.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But Trump is now making clear he wants a major crime bill, too — and fast.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The president has spent weeks bashing Democrats on crime, particularly governors who are seen as key 2028 presidential race contenders, and he’s eager to leverage a winning and unifying issue for Republicans on Capitol Hill.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But just how ambitious the crime bill ends up being remains an open question. Even the D.C.-focused legislation stands to be a significant undertaking on Capitol Hill next month — with GOP leaders already scrambling to hammer out plans to fund the government, pass a defense authorization bill and a litany of other items this fall.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>96</id>
            <title>The Supreme Court in Washington.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/26/justice-department-supreme-court-foreign-aid-00527929</link>
            <description>The solicitor general argues that only Congress has the authority to challenge impoundment of federal money.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-26T19:55:20</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>8</id>
                <name>Josh</name>
                <surname>Gerstein</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\e396de5a-9a6b-46a6-97ee-387f675263e6.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration is asking the Supreme Court to allow the president to withhold billions of dollars in congressionally appropriated foreign aid before the fiscal year ends on Sept. 30.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Justice Department filed &lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/26076098-globalhealthscotusapp082625/" target="_blank"&gt;an emergency appeal&lt;/a&gt; with the high court Tuesday, asking the justices to pause a federal district judge’s order that requires the administration to come up with a plan to lay out the money by the deadline next month.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Solicitor General John Sauer argued in the new filing that groups representing aid contractors have no legal basis to force such spending and that it's up to Congress to challenge executive branch spending shortfalls under a 1974 law, the Impoundment Control Act.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Congress did not upset the delicate interbranch balance by allowing for unlimited, unconstrained private suits,” Sauer wrote. “Any lingering dispute about the proper disposition of funds that the President seeks to rescind shortly before they expire should be left to the political branches, not effectively prejudged by the district court.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;While Sauer's submission is framed as an argument to defer to Congress, he also makes clear that the administration believes Trump has authority to engage in so-called pocket recissions that would occur so late in the fiscal year that it would be impractical for Congress to reverse them.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;It’s the latest escalation in Trump’s effort to wrest the power of the purse from Congress, one that has alarmed lower courts and rankled even some Republicans in Congress.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump and his budget architect Russell Vought have long sought to challenge the 1974 law, which establishes strict procedures when the president intends to cancel spending authorized by Congress. Though the president can briefly pause some spending, he must get congressional permission to cancel it altogether through a process known as “rescission.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/13/humanitarian-groups-cannot-challenge-trumps-impoundment-of-foreign-aid-grants-appeals-court-rules-00507106" target="_blank"&gt;a three-judge panel of the D.C. Circuit Court of Appeals ruled&lt;/a&gt;, 2-1, that only Congress’ comptroller general — the leader of the Government Accountability Office — has the power to challenge allegedly unlawful impoundments by the president. Groups that rely on foreign aid funding and claim the right to sue over withheld grants are asking the full bench of the D.C. Circuit to reverse that conclusion, but the full court has not yet acted.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;For now, an earlier order from U.S. District Judge Amir Ali in favor of the aid groups remains in effect. Ali, a Biden appointee, mandated formal obligation of the funds by the end of September. That order is presently due to be set aside unless the full D.C. Circuit steps in — but the Trump administration seems eager to get the issue in front of the Supreme Court quickly.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Sauer asked the justices to rule by Sept. 2 or to put in place a temporary order that the government need not comply with Ali's directive.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;An official with one of the groups challenging the funding holdbacks, the AIDS Vaccine Advocacy Coalition, said it wasn't surprising that the administration is rushing the dispute to the high court.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Time and again, this administration has shown their disdain for foreign assistance and a disregard for people’s lives in the United States and around the world. But even more broadly and dangerously, this administration’s actions further erodes Congress’s role and responsibility as an equal branch of government,” the coalition's executive director, Mitchell Warren, said in a statement. “The question being put to SCOTUS is whether they will be complicit in further eroding the constitutional commitment to checks and balance.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Carmen Paun contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>97</id>
            <title>President Donald Trump speaks during a press briefing in the James S. Brady Press Briefing Room at the White House Aug. 11, 2025. (Francis Chung/POLITICO via AP Images)</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/25/grassley-trump-blue-slip-criticism-00522724</link>
            <description>Trump is warning he will try to sue over the precedent and criticizing Senate Judiciary Committee Chair Chuck Grassley for not ceding to his demands to nix the practice.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-25T09:29:43</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>6</id>
                <name>Jordain</name>
                <surname>Carney</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\976e5a80-77ee-4aa4-abcf-2fe2df55f568.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump is escalating his war against a long-time Senate precedent that allows home-state senators to effectively block district court and U.S. attorney nominees they oppose.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Over the past 24 hours, Trump has gone from calling out Senate Judiciary Chair Chuck Grassley for upholding the so-called blue slip practice to announcing plans to launch a long-shot lawsuit arguing that it’s unconstitutional.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We're … going to be filing a lawsuit on blue slipping,” Trump told reporters Monday. “You know, blue slips make it impossible for me as president to appoint a judge or U.S. Attorney because they have a gentlemen's agreement. It's nothing memorialized, it's a gentlemen's agreement that's about 100 years old.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Justice Department did not immediately respond to a request for comment. However, an executive branch lawsuit against Congress for its own internal procedures for handling presidential nominations seems like a legal nonstarter.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Courts have long been wary of intervening in political disputes between the other branches of government, instead allowing them to use their own formidable checks and balances to reach “accommodations” or negotiate agreements. The blue slip isn’t a formal Senate rule, or in the Constitution, but is instead a precedent upheld by tradition and the party in power.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump’s threat, however, marks an escalation of a pressure campaign he has been waging — without success — against Grassley over blue slips for more than a month.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Tensions were &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/21/alina-habba-new-jersey-us-attorney-ruling-00518559" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;newly inflamed late last week&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, when a U.S. district judge ruled that Alina Habba, an acting U.S. attorney in New Jersey, had been serving in the role without legal authority since July 1.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump had tried to keep Habba in charge of the office after her interim appointment expired. That effort &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/07/24/trump-alina-habba-new-jersey-nomination-00476033" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;included withdrawing her Senate nomination&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which was already stalled because of opposition by New Jersey Democratic Sens. Cory Booker and Andy Kim&lt;b&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;On Sunday evening, &lt;a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/115086695163847248" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Trump posted on Truth Social&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that Grassley should scrap the blue slip practice, which the president called an “old and outdated ‘custom.’”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump continued: “The only candidates that I can get confirmed for these most important positions are, believe it or not, Democrats! Chuck Grassley should allow strong Republican candidates to ascend to these very vital and powerful roles, and tell the Democrats, as they often tell us, to go to HELL!”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Republicans got rid of this same precedent for appeals court nominees during Trump’s first term, but they &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/19/senate-republicans-blue-slip-00513489?experience_id=EXYF89KVT5UQ&amp;amp;template_id=OTJIR2CRKUD6&amp;amp;variant_id=OTV632IE7RALS&amp;amp;is_login_link=true" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;have so far rebuffed Trump’s calls&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for them to do the same for district court and U.S. attorney nominations. Many GOP senators believe that if they bend to Trump’s demand now, it would only come back to bite them later, when they find themselves back in the minority and unable to stop nominees from a Democratic administration.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Grassley spent the first half of Monday morning defending his position. In one &lt;a href="https://x.com/ChuckGrassley/status/1959956529005662462" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;social media post&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, he said that, as chair of the Judiciary Committee, “I set Pres Trump noms up for SUCCESS NOT FAILURE.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“A U.S. Atty/district judge nominee without a blue slip does not [have] the votes to get confirmed on the Senate floor &amp;amp; they don’t [have] the votes to get out of [committee],” he added.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://x.com/chuckgrassley/status/1959962735959011463?s=46" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;a subsequent X post Monday&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Grassley said the administration had withdrawn Habba’s nomination and that the committee “never received any of the paperwork needed for the Senate to vet her nomination.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://x.com/ChuckGrassley/status/1959996843779362985" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;another post&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, he justified his decision to maintain the precedent by pointing out how Republicans used blue slips during the Biden administration to keep "30 LIBERALS OFF BENCH THAT PRES TRUMP CAN NOW FILL W[ITH] CONSERVATIVES."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Grassley on Monday was also fending off not just criticism from Trump but from Habba herself, who took on Grassley and Sen Thom Tillis &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/24/alina-habba-slams-senate-blue-slips-00522501" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;by name&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in a TV interview on Sunday morning.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“This tradition that Senator Grassley is upholding effectively prevents anybody in a blue state from going through into Senate to then be voted on,” Habba said on “Sunday Morning Futures with Maria Bartiromo.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I would say to Senator Tillis and Senator Grassley, you are becoming part of the issue,” she added. “You are becoming part of the antithesis of what we fought for four years.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Tillis, a North Carolina Republican and a member of the Judiciary Committee, said recently that he would continue to honor the blue slip for district court and U.S. attorney nominations even if the precedent was rescinded. That means he would oppose all relevant nominees who lacked support from their home state senators.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://x.com/SenThomTillis/status/1960006458302406772" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;In a statement on X Monday&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Tillis defended Grassley, calling him a “principled conservative who wants to keep radical liberals off the bench.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Getting rid of the blue slip is a terrible, short-sighted ploy that paves the path for Democrats to ram through extremist liberal judges in red states over the long-term,” said Tillis. “It’s why radical liberal groups have been pushing to get rid of the blue slip for years — Republicans shouldn’t fall for it.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Kyle Cheney contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>98</id>
            <title>Just two Republicans have emerged to take on Democratic freshman Rep. Nellie Pou.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/24/new-jersey-recruitment-congress-00519623</link>
            <description>The 2026 fight for control of Congress runs through New Jersey’s swing seats. But one party is arriving better prepared than the other.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-24T13:00:00</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>9</id>
                <name>Matt</name>
                <surname>Friedman</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\42a5d5ed-c9b7-42ef-b306-232c95ec9f7e.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;As Republicans look to flip House seats through redistricting in Texas and other red states, they have a pickup opportunity in what was once deep blue North Jersey, without having to redraw any lines.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In the state’s heavily Hispanic 9th Congressional District, the Democrat who was widely thought to be a shoo-in &lt;a href="https://subscriber.politicopro.com/article/2024/11/nellie-pou-will-replace-pascrell-after-surprisingly-close-race-00187247" target="_blank"&gt;won by just five points last year&lt;/a&gt;, and President Donald Trump narrowly won the district after losing it the last two cycles. Yet, even amid talk of New Jersey becoming a purple state, just two Republican candidates have stepped forward to run in the district.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, in the one Republican-held seat Democrats have a realistic opportunity to pick up, in Central Jersey’s 7th District, Democrats are &lt;a href="https://subscriber.politicopro.com/article/2025/08/7th-district-democratic-field-gets-even-more-crowded-with-climate-scientists-entrance-00497757" target="_blank"&gt;practically falling over each other to challenge two-term Republican&lt;/a&gt; Rep. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/196429" data-person-id="196429"&gt;Tom Kean Jr&lt;/a&gt;. Nine Democratic candidates — including several with a proven ability to raise funds and made-for-campaign bios like former Navy Black Hawk pilot, physician and climate scientist — have declared their candidacies with nearly a year to go before the primary.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Democrats in New Jersey feel like the stakes are existential — literally existential — in these midterm elections,” said Hunterdon County Democratic Chair Tom Malinowski, a former 7th District representative whom Kean ousted in 2022. “I’m not sure Republicans feel quite as strongly.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump’s &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/11/06/new-jersey-swing-state-red-00187965" target="_blank"&gt;remarkably narrow six-point loss in New Jersey last year&lt;/a&gt; was widely seen as a sign one of the bluest states in the nation was turning purple. And there are other indicators that Democratic dominance is fading in the state. Since the 2020 election, Republicans have shaved Democrats' statewide voter registration advantage from more than 1 million to 864,825. And in the 2021 election, Republican Jack Ciattarelli — yet again the GOP nominee for governor this year — &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/states/new-jersey/story/2021/11/12/ciattarelli-concedes-in-nj-governors-race-vows-to-run-again-in-2025-1393017" target="_blank"&gt;came within just three points of ousting Democratic Gov. Phil Murphy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But presidential elections turn out more lower-propensity voters than midterms. And wealthier suburban districts like the 7th have had higher turnout than the more working-class 9th. Candidate recruitment and fundraising are some of the few tangible measures of where the political winds are blowing. And in New Jersey’s 2026 House races, Democrats are so far dominating on both fronts.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Republicans are calling the 9th a swing district. They’re talking about a potential investment,” said Micah Rasmussen, director of the Rebovich Institute for New Jersey Politics at Rider University. “But I think they understand they’re not going to get the turnout they’re looking for in a midterm. I think it’s a different kind of priority than the 7th District, where turnout is not going to be as dependent on the presidential race.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The heavy interest from Democrats seeking to oust Kean is reminiscent of the blue wave 2018 midterms, when Democrats &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/states/new-jersey/story/2018/11/07/new-jersey-democrats-flip-3-house-seats-in-major-victories-685749" target="_blank"&gt;flipped four New Jersey Republican-held House seats&lt;/a&gt;. Back then, seven Democrats lined up to run for the 7th District seat — and that was when the district boundaries made it slightly easier for Democrats to win it.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Even in South Jersey’s 2nd District, where Republican Rep. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/196450" data-person-id="196450"&gt;Jeff Van Drew&lt;/a&gt; won reelection last year by 17 points, three Democrats have filed to run in 2026 — more than Republicans in the 9th District. The same goes for North Jersey’s 11th District, where three Democrats have already filed with the FEC to replace Rep. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/307338" data-person-id="307338"&gt;Mikie Sherrill&lt;/a&gt;, the Democratic nominee for governor, in case she wins the governorship this November and vacates the seat.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In the 9th District, Republican Billy Prempeh is running again in his fourth straight campaign for the seat since 2020, and just one other Republican has so far come forward: Rosemary Pino, a councilmember in Clifton. No one else has even teased a candidacy yet to take on Democratic freshman Rep. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/196439" data-person-id="196439"&gt;Nellie Pou&lt;/a&gt;, though Republicans are optimistic other candidates will emerge.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;While national Republicans POLITICO spoke to had yet to commit to any candidates, Prempeh — who narrowly lost in 2024 — believes he can be their man.“I feel supported by the Republican Party. I think they see the same things that I see: This district is very winnable. I think I’m making the right choice,” he said in a phone interview.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But Prempeh, never a strong fundraiser, has barely raised anything for his next race. His last campaign finance report, filed mid-July, showed a balance of negative $634.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We ran that race with under $50,000, while my opponent spent close to $500,000 against me,” Prempeh said. “I’m very good at running a race, even with small resources.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Pino, as a Hispanic woman, could be a demographic ideal for a Republican candidate in the district. But she’s already demonstrated vulnerability. Shortly after she declared her candidacy, Prempeh pointed out that a group she led &lt;a href="https://x.com/BillyPrempeh/status/1945459826072420708" target="_blank"&gt;last year endorsed Pou against him&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Passaic County GOP Chair Peter Murphy, whose county makes up much of the district, said that it’s a tempting target for Republicans and that he sees more candidates emerging, including from next door in Bergen County. “I really do believe more Republicans are going to be coming out of the 9th district. I think you’re going to see a lot more coming. By the primary I could see four or five,” he said.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Republicans are pointing to Central Jersey’s 7th District race as a potential mess, while noting Pou in the 9th District could face her own primary challenge.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Many of the Democratic candidates in the 7th live just outside the district, including until recently Rebecca Bennett, a former Navy Blackhawk pilot and the first to declare (she moved into the district this summer, her campaign said).. So far, she has captured the most attention from national Democrats. But several rivals have already raised hundreds of thousands of dollars, and Republicans warn that in such a large primary, the candidates will work to drag the field to the left, hurting the eventual nominee’s chances in the general election.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Bennett said she felt called to run. “I can’t explain it any other way that a switch flipped in my brain, and I told my husband, ‘I have to run for office now,’” she said. “I really love this country. I took an oath to support and defend the Constitution.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Republicans see Pou as a potentially weak incumbent, never having had competitive general elections during her time in the state Legislature and already facing buzz about potential primary challengers, &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/newsletters/new-jersey-playbook/2025/08/07/sayegh-considers-pou-challenge-00496384" target="_blank"&gt;including from the mayor of Paterson&lt;/a&gt;, by far the largest city in the district.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Kean, by contrast, is a two-term incumbent with a family name that goes back generations in New Jersey. His father, Tom Kean Sr., is the state’s most popular former governor.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Whoever prevails will be wearing the progressive crown, completely broke and too battered to even compete against Rep. Tom Kean Jr.,” said Maureen O’Toole, a spokesperson for the National Republican Congressional Committee.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Harrison Neely, a campaign consultant for Kean, said the field is “a clear signal of Democrat party chaos and disarray. They can’t unite behind a candidate because they have no organization, no vision and nothing to offer.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In addition to Bennett, the 7th District field includes: Tina Shah, a medical doctor; Michael Roth, a former top official at the Small Business Administration; businessman Brian Varela; former Summit councilmember Greg Vartan; criminal justice professor Beth Adubato; attorney Valentina Mendoza; and little-known Michael Garth. Megan O’Rourke, a former Biden administration climate scientist, became the latest to declare her candidacy this month.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Democrats see echoes of the 2018 Democratic wave, when seven candidates filed to run in the district’s primary. Eventually, the field narrowed down to three, and the nominee — Malinowski — ousted Leonard Lance that November after 10 years in Congress.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Recent polling shows Trump is unpopular in New Jersey — between 11 points and 18 points under water, according to two recent polls. Still, that’s more popular than he was at this point in 2018.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The 7th and 9th Districts both encapsulate a shift in the Democratic and Republican coalitions. The wealthier, suburban and whiter 7th has many traditional Republican voters who began shifting left after Trump’s first election. That’s in contrast to the more working-class, Hispanic-plurality 9th, which has recently moved towards Republicans.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But so far, the signs point to a tough time flipping the 9th District in a midterm, said Rasmussen, the Rebovich Institute director.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Republicans realize that their success in the 9th depends on presidential-level turnout that they’re not going to get in 2026,” he said. “They could get it again in 2028, although presumably Trump isn’t going to be on the ballot.”&lt;/p&gt;CORRECTION: An earlier version of this article misstated Democratic candidate Rebecca Bennett's residency status. She moved into the 7th Congressional District this summer, according to her campaign.</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>99</id>
            <title>nbsp;want safer communities," House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries said.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/24/hakeem-jeffries-national-guard-chicago-00521904</link>
            <description>"We should continue to support local law enforcement and not simply allow Donald Trump to play games with the lives of the American people," he said.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-24T10:50:48</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>7</id>
                <name>Gregory</name>
                <surname>Svirnovskiy</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\648e1bf8-2ea2-41ba-ac43-183a163cecb6.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Democratic House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries on Sunday slammed President Donald Trump's statement that he might deploy National Guard troops to Chicago, as the White House flexes federal power in the name of fighting crime.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"We should continue to support local law enforcement and not simply allow Donald Trump to play games with the lives of the American people as part of his effort to manufacture a crisis and create a distraction because he's deeply unpopular," Jeffries told CNN's Dana Bash on "State of the Union."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/22/trump-national-guard-chicago-new-york-00519849" target="_blank"&gt;told reporters last Friday&lt;/a&gt; he was weighing sending troops to Chicago and New York, after &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/11/trump-dc-police-federal-control-00502708" target="_blank"&gt;federalizing Washington's police department&lt;/a&gt; and bringing in the National Guard in mid-August. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Almost immediately, Illinois Democrats responded with force. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"An authoritarian power grab of major cities," &lt;a href="https://x.com/JBPritzker/status/1958965961815392342" target="_blank"&gt;Gov. JB Pritzker called the move in a Friday post on X&lt;/a&gt;, placing it as the sole item on a list of "things People are NOT begging for" and needling Trump for his administration's handling of the Epstein files. Chicago &lt;a href="https://x.com/ChicagosMayor/status/1959001460366061976" target="_blank"&gt;Mayor Brandon Johnson said on X&lt;/a&gt; that deploying the national guard could "inflame tensions between residents and law enforcement" and "threaten to undermine the historic progress we have made" in fighting crime. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Democrats are skeptical of the president's motivations, since &lt;a href="https://www.wbez.org/criminal-justice/2025/07/25/chicagos-crime-decline-is-part-of-a-national-trend-researchers-say" target="_blank"&gt;crime in major cities — including Chicago —&lt;/a&gt; has been on a notable decline since the Covid-19 pandemic. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The National Guard troops detailed to the nation's capital were &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/22/dc-national-guard-weapons-00519563" target="_blank"&gt;authorized to carry&lt;/a&gt; “service-issue weapons” last week, and several &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/newsletters/playbook/2025/08/17/trumps-crackdown-hits-washington-00512891" target="_blank"&gt;Republican states have sent their own National Guard&lt;/a&gt; members to join the ones already dispatched to D.C. The Washington &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/21/trump-patrol-dc-military-00518079" target="_blank"&gt;deployment will continue&lt;/a&gt; "for a while," Trump said Thursday, &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/20/dc-trump-police-poll-00515947" target="_blank"&gt;even though nearly 80 percent of residents&lt;/a&gt; told a poll they oppose the president's actions.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Jeffries pushed back on the notion that Democrats' opposition to Trump's national guard deployments meant the party isn't serious about maintaining law and order, and accused the president of "exacerbating" the national mental health crisis that has contributed to violence.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"As Democrats, we want safer communities," he told Bash. "We want to continue to make sure that crime can go down as it's doing in Chicago, in New York, in Washington, D.C., and other places. And to do that, we should support local law enforcement. We should make sure that the flood of guns into these communities is cut off."&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>100</id>
            <title>Rep. Thomas Massie (R-Ky.) holds a copy of a bill he cosponsored with Rep. Ro Khanna (D-Calif.) to force the House to vote on the complete release of the government's files on Jeffrey Epstein as he speaks with reporters outside the U.S. Capitol July 21, 2025. (Francis Chung/POLITICO via AP Images)</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/22/epstein-files-land-on-capitol-hill-00519851</link>
            <description>Now comes the waiting game as congressional Republicans and the DOJ coordinate on redactions.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-22T13:53:19</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>10</id>
                <name>Hailey</name>
                <surname>Fuchs</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\af76328f-70e2-4da0-8703-01d4630a86bd.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Congress has officially received the first batch of Jeffrey Epstein files.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Justice Department turned over a tranche of materials related to the case against the late, convicted sex offender Friday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;These documents — transmitted in compliance with a subpoena issued earlier this month by the House Oversight and Government Reform Committee — represent only a portion of what DOJ has in its possession and it’s not immediately clear what sort of information lawmakers currently have available to them. The documents are expected to have heavy redactions.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Oversight Committee now plans to &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/22/congress-trump-doj-epstein-files-00519316" target="_blank"&gt;review the materials&lt;/a&gt;, with both Democrats and Republicans having access. While under a typical arrangement, the majority — in this case Republicans — would control its disclosure, either party could release the materials unilaterally.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Committee Republicans have pledged to coordinate with the Justice Department to protect the identities of victims and ensure certain details do not complicate ongoing criminal matters. A spokesperson for the panel's chair, Rep. James Comer (R-Ky.), said in a statement that DOJ's production of materials Friday "contains thousands of pages of documents."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"The Committee intends to make these records public after thorough review to ensure any victims’ identification and child sexual abuse material are redacted," the spokesperson said. "The Committee will also consult with the DOJ to ensure any documents released do not negatively impact ongoing criminal cases and investigations.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Democrats also intend to review the files before releasing them publicly, according to a person familiar with Oversight Democrats’ planning, speaking on condition of anonymity to share party strategy.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"We just received the first batch of the Epstein files from Trump’s Department of Justice. Our team is beginning a careful review process. We will share additional information as we learn more," said ranking member Robert Garcia (D-Calif.) in a &lt;a href="https://x.com/RepRobertGarcia/status/1958968641472647322?t=RJfAsH5NRX7C93rmeRL-QQ&amp;amp;s=19" target="_blank"&gt;social media post.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;There’s no current time estimate for when the public will be able to see the files. One personal familiar with the transmission of the files, granted anonymity to describe private details, said the tranche encompasses more than 33,000 documents.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Epstein saga has brought together strange bedfellows in Congress. Democrats sought to stoke divisions among Donald Trump’s base over the administration’s initial decision to withhold much of the information in the Epstein case after the president’s allies for years clamored for the release of the files. Meanwhile, many Republicans called the administration’s perceived about-face an affront to earlier promises of bringing transparency around the charges against Epstein, who died by suicide in his jail cell in 2019.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The House Oversight subpoena for the Epstein files was the culmination of this unlikely bipartisan partnership, where committee Democrats were able to get enough Republicans to join them in a surprise vote to force the release of the DOJ materials.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Justice Department’s compliance, however, is unlikely to satisfy clamoring for a more expansive unsealing of the documents, with plans from Reps. Thomas Massie (R-Ky.) and Ro Khanna (D-Calif.) to force a floor vote on their resolution to compel the full release of the Epstein files soon after Congress returns Sept. 2 from its month-long recess.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Oversight GOP spokesperson defended the administration's approach to delivering the files to lawmakers.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"The Trump DOJ is providing records at a far quicker pace than anything the Biden DOJ ever provided," the spokesperson said. "In fact, former Attorney General Garland obstructed Chairman Comer’s subpoena for the audio of Special Counsel Hur’s interview with President Biden to hide his cognitive decline."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Comer has an ongoing investigation into alleged efforts inside former President Joe Biden's White House to hide evidence he was no longer fit for office.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;At around the same time word trickled out that Congress was in possession of the first batch of Epstein documents, Deputy Attorney General Todd Blanche &lt;a href="https://x.com/DAGToddBlanche/status/1958963761345163555" target="_blank"&gt;announced the public release&lt;/a&gt;of audio and redacted transcripts of his interview with Ghislaine Maxwell, Epstein's co-conspirator who is currently serving a 20-year prison sentence.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>101</id>
            <title>Rep. Thomas Massie holds a copy of a bill he cosponsored with Rep. Ro Khanna to force the House to vote on the complete release of the government's files on Jeffrey Epstein.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/22/congress-trump-doj-epstein-files-00519316</link>
            <description>The DOJ is expected to make heavy redactions for an initial tranche of Epstein documents.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-22T03:45:00</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>10</id>
                <name>Hailey</name>
                <surname>Fuchs</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\7dcfe262-9f74-4db5-8604-1bf68101a881.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;The Justice Department is expected on Friday to start handing the first batch of Jeffrey Epstein files over to Congress. But it may be a while before lawmakers get the information they want — if ever.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The DOJ is taking a piecemeal approach to transmitting documents to Capitol Hill, pursuant to a &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/05/epstein-subpoenas-department-of-justice-00494129" target="_blank"&gt;subpoena issued this month&lt;/a&gt; by the House Oversight and Government Reform Committee after Democrats on the panel forced the matter.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The committee, led by Kentucky Republican Rep. James Comer, anticipates receiving &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/18/doj-turning-over-epstein-files-capitol-hill-00513606" target="_blank"&gt;an initial tranche&lt;/a&gt; of files related to the convicted sex offender by the end of the day Aug. 22. Making these materials public, however, will be a slow, deliberative process.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;That’s because House Oversight intends to coordinate with the Justice Department on taking steps to shield the names of the women who were victims of Epstein, who died by suicide in 2019, and information around ongoing criminal cases. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“The Committee intends to make the records public after thorough review to ensure all victims’ identification and child sexual abuse material are redacted,” said an Oversight Committee spokesperson, granted anonymity to share details about the panel’s internal activities. “The Committee will also consult with the DOJ to ensure any documents released do not negatively impact ongoing criminal cases and investigations.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;If the Justice Department follows precedent, both Democrats and Republicans on House Oversight would get access to the materials. While under a typical arrangement, the majority — in this case Republicans — would control its disclosure, either party could release the materials unilaterally.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Democrats, however, intend to review the files before releasing them publicly, according to a person familiar with Oversight Democrats’ planning, speaking on condition of anonymity to share internal party strategy.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The files they receive could include FBI reports of witness interviews; materials seized from the searches of Epstein’s vast properties in New York, the Virgin Islands, Palm Beach and New Mexico; and the affidavits used to gain permission from judges to execute those searches.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;There are a variety of complicating factors to consider, among them the ongoing legal challenge that Ghislaine Maxwell, a longtime Epstein associate, is pursuing against her 20-year conviction for sex trafficking crimes. House Oversight previously &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/08/01/congress/maxwell-hearing-postponed-00489019" target="_blank"&gt;subpoenaed Maxwell&lt;/a&gt; for testimony and is negotiating the conditions of the interview with her legal team. Maxwell, who was sentenced in 2021, is demanding that she be granted immunity from further criminal proceedings in exchange for her cooperation.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The plodding process is unlikely to satisfy demands for transparency from lawmakers on both sides of the aisle, though. And House GOP leaders shouldn’t expect to return from the August recess free from the drama that consumed them in July.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“After months of stonewalling, calling Epstein files a hoax, and telling people nothing but porn exists in their possession, the administration now admits the files exist, and agrees to release some of them,” Rep. Thomas Massie (R-Ky.) said in &lt;a href="https://x.com/RepThomasMassie/status/1957598660725748030" target="_blank"&gt;a social media post this week.&lt;/a&gt; “Americans want transparency though, not smoke and mirrors.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Massie, with Rep. Ro Khanna (D-Calif.), has been leading the charge to force a floor vote on a resolution that would compel the release of the Epstein files, and the two men say they’ll follow through on plans when Congress returns to use procedural maneuvers to call the measure up without leadership’s consent.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Massie-Khanna resolution would call for the materials to be made public with redactions only for the purposes of protecting names of victims, hiding sexually explicit content and in instances where ongoing legal cases could be compromised. In other words, the lawmakers want to guarantee the identities of Epstein’s associates, if applicable, are revealed.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Last month, Speaker Mike Johnson said Republicans should give the DOJ time to reveal the documents in a responsible manner that would respect the privacy of Epstein’s victims. However, President Donald Trump — who &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2019/08/09/epstein-mar-a-lago-trump-1456221" target="_blank"&gt;had ties to Epstein, a well-known financier&lt;/a&gt; — was also pushing to move past the issue after his allies had &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/07/12/trump-epstein-investigation-pam-bondi-00449926" target="_blank"&gt;stoked conspiracy theories for years&lt;/a&gt; about what authorities were hiding.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Yet Massie, Khanna and allies would not budge from their stance that members must be allowed to vote to bring the files to light, disrupting the Rules Committee that tees up floor consideration for most legislation. Leaders opted to send their members home a few days ahead of schedule for the summer recess rather than stay in Washington to take politically uncomfortable votes.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Democrats are also signaling they won’t be satisfied by the DOJ’s game plan and will continue to make the issue a political headache for Republicans.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Releasing the Epstein files in batches just continues this White House cover-up. The American people will not accept anything short of the full, unredacted Epstein files,” Rep. Robert Garcia, the top Democrat on the Oversight Committee, said in a statement. “We will keep pressing until the American people get the truth — every document, every fact, in full. The administration must comply with our subpoena, by law.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Efforts to draw a wedge in the GOP over the Epstein files were taking place as far away as Texas this week, where Gene Wu, chair of the state’s House Democratic Caucus, offered an amendment to delay Republicans’ mid-decade redistricting efforts until after the release of Epstein materials.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, back in Washington, lawmakers will regroup on Capitol Hill on Sept. 2 with just four weeks left to avert a government shutdown, and there’s already concern in GOP leadership over the time the House could waste continuing to fight over perceived distractions.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I’d really like to see this resolved, if possible, before we get back,” Rep. Virginia Foxx (R-Va.), chair of the House Rules Committee, told reporters this week. “We’re going to have a lot of work to do when we get back in September. I’ve already looked at my September calendar, and it looks pretty busy.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Foxx, whose committee work was derailed by members’ efforts to force Epstein-related votes, called the saga “a tempest in a teapot.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In February, the Department of Justice released what it called the “first phase” of documents related to the Epstein investigation, which has been a fixation of some of the president’s supporters. It has long been public that Trump — along with other prominent figures, like Bill Clinton — are &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/01/03/unsealed-documents-jeffrey-epstein-associates-00133771" target="_blank"&gt;referenced in documents previously released&lt;/a&gt; in court cases surrounding Epstein. But Trump is not accused of any wrongdoing linked to Epstein.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The real firestorm, however, began in earnest in early July, when the department quietly released a memo saying the federal government did not find evidence of a so-called Epstein “client list.” &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/07/18/nx-s1-5470152/the-fbi-says-there-is-no-epstein-list-angering-much-of-president-trumps-base" target="_blank"&gt;Conspiracists had long postulated&lt;/a&gt; that Epstein kept such a list of people with whom he trafficked young women, and that it was being hidden to protect the rich and powerful.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;No additional disclosures would be forthcoming, the unsigned memo said, which quickly — and predictably — set off a complicated political quagmire for the president and the GOP amid accusations that the administration was reneging on its promise for transparency.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump, in an effort to quash the outrage, asked Attorney General Pam Bondi to seek the release of grand jury materials in the most recent investigations of Epstein and Maxwell in New York, as well as an earlier federal probe of Epstein in Florida. In recent weeks, all three judges assigned to resolve the unsealing requests rebuffed the administration, with &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/20/epstein-grand-jury-materials-ruling-00516558" target="_blank"&gt;the most recent rejection coming Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;video id="http://vod.politico.com/media/v1/pmp4/static/clear/1155968404/d141bfca-f006-4a45-9755-cd9dee431c85/543467c1-1a7b-4778-85b5-0e4a3ad387b1/main.mp4" title="Audio: Ghislaine Maxwell says she never saw Donald Trump receive a massage" data-description="lead image" poster="https://cf-images.us-east-1.prod.boltdns.net/v1/static/1155968404/d141bfca-f006-4a45-9755-cd9dee431c85/744c12ff-2fa7-4001-9292-8795017587f1/1280x720/match/image.jpg"&gt;&lt;source src="http://vod.politico.com/media/v1/pmp4/static/clear/1155968404/d141bfca-f006-4a45-9755-cd9dee431c85/543467c1-1a7b-4778-85b5-0e4a3ad387b1/main.mp4" type="video/mp4"&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;p&gt;The judges said the department hadn’t justified taking the unusual step of unsealing the secret files and that, in any event, most of material in the files had already been made public through Maxwell’s trial or other means.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Still, even if the grand jury transcripts and exhibits were made public, they represent a tiny fraction of the material the Justice Department possesses in the Epstein and Maxwell investigative files that are the subject of the congressional subpoena.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;When the House Oversight Committee interviewed Trump's former attorney general, Bill Barr, as part of its probe into the Epstein matter earlier this month, Barr told congressional investigators that he did not know why the documents were being withheld, according to a person familiar with his testimony and granted anonymity to describe the private conversation. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The lack of transparency around the process, however, might have to do with the fact that some grand jury materials may need court approval, Barr suggested, and that current policy prohibits the release of unsubstantiated information.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the House Oversight subpoena currently represents the best chance for bringing some information to light — and for the Trump administration to get limited details released to satisfy those clamoring for action.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Longstanding DOJ policies as well as a federal law — the Privacy Act of 1974 — limit disclosures about living individuals investigated for potential crimes. However, that law and those DOJ rules do not apply to Congress, which is generally free to ignore individuals’ pleas for discretion. DOJ has sometimes used that distinction to effectively make sensitive information public by transmitting it to Congress — with GOP and Democratic lawmakers then able to cherry pick what of the sensitive information they choose to share.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;A DOJ spokesperson did not respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Erica Orden, Josh Gerstein and Jordain Carney contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>102</id>
            <title>Vice President JD Vance reacts as he arrives for the Conservative Political Action Conference at the Gaylord National Resort and Convention Center in National Harbor, Maryland, on Feb. 20, 2025.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/21/republicans-trump-vance-megabill-00516964</link>
            <description>Vice President JD Vance will be in Georgia on Thursday to take a stab at pitching a massive bill that hasn’t yet been fully implemented.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-21T03:45:00</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>6</id>
                <name>Jordain</name>
                <surname>Carney</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\35efd810-d33b-4fca-93ee-ec0233cd8251.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Republicans are facing a major obstacle as they try to tout the potential benefits of President Donald Trump’s “big, beautiful bill”: They need voters to take their word on it for now.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;GOP lawmakers and top administration officials are using August to make a country-wide sales pitch for their crowning legislative achievement — a massive &lt;a href="https://legislation.politicopro.com/bill/US_119_HR_1" target="_blank"&gt;tax, spending and domestic policy package&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The party sees this month as crucial for gaining ground in the messaging war with Democrats over the new law, which pairs an extension of Trump’s 2017 tax cuts with some of his campaign promises like “no tax on tips,” plus more funding for immigration enforcement and the military.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The White House is dispatching Vice President JD Vance to Georgia on Thursday, where he’ll talk about the megabill’s “working family tax cuts,” according to his spokesperson.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Republicans want to be the ones to define their megabill with voters ahead of next year’s midterms, where the GOP’s unified control of Congress is at stake. They saw Democrats try to shop their signature climate law in 2022 — &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2023/02/10/biden-takes-his-climate-law-on-the-road-00081799" target="_blank"&gt;only for most Americans&lt;/a&gt; to say they either never heard of it, or were swayed by Republicans’ counterargument it was a “green new scam.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But the GOP megabill is less than two months old, and many of its purported boons — like new and expanded tax cuts and savings accounts for children under 18 — won’t be fully felt by voters until 2026, making it harder for Republicans to reinforce what they see as the law’s advantages.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, Republicans are going up against Democrats embarking on their own nationwide tour to denigrate what they call the “big, ugly bill" and its dire shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“It’s hard for people to realize anything that they haven’t seen yet — all they are doing is hearing it. And we all want to go out … and say, ‘This is the positive from this, this is what’s happened,’” Sen. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/374701" data-person-id="374701"&gt;Tommy Tuberville&lt;/a&gt; (R-Ala.) said this week. “There’s going to be a lot of substance to this, it just all has to go into effect.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, Tuberville acknowledged that his own state would “pay a little bit of a price” because of changes to the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program, which will force the state to cover more of the program’s cost.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Asked if he was worried selling the bill would be harder than expected, Tuberville hedged. “No — well again, you don’t know until the end of the day, how this bill is going to be reacted to.” He predicted the next six months would determine the law’s reception.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Yet the GOP’s efforts to preview the megabill’s forthcoming perks come as Democrats are also using August to flood the zone — including visiting red states and typically safe GOP districts — to warn about the law’s impending cuts to Medicaid and SNAP.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“House Republicans have betrayed their constituents in passing the Big, Ugly Law which benefits the wealthiest few and leaves everyday families behind,” Democratic Congressional Campaign Committee Chair &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/198811" data-person-id="198811"&gt;Suzan DelBene&lt;/a&gt; (Wash.) said in a statement Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Republicans are well aware that they are facing a tidal wave of Democratic criticism heading into a midterm election cycle, when the party in power typically loses seats. While Republicans still have an edge in the Senate map, Democrats have managed to score major recruiting wins in key races and are cautiously optimistic about their chances of flipping the House in 2026.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;One House Republican, granted anonymity to speak candidly, said in a recent interview that the party has a good case to make on the GOP megabill but they need to hammer it harder.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We have to do better,” the Republican said. “We have to pound that over and over again: Constituents are going to feel it.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The House GOP’s campaign arm circulated a memo late last month with guidance for how to message about the law, &lt;a href="https://www.nrcc.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Make-August-Count.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;calling the congressional August recess&lt;/a&gt; a “critical opportunity to continue to define how this legislation will help every voter and push back on Democrat fearmongering.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Since then, House and Senate Republicans have, indeed, fanned out across the country to tout state-specific benefits from their megabill they pledge will come soon. Republican Rep. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/313246" data-person-id="313246"&gt;Mariannette Miller-Meeks&lt;/a&gt;, for instance, visited three Iowa manufacturers as part of a tour to highlight funding for workforce and trade school training.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Senate Majority Leader &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/51242" data-person-id="51242"&gt;John Thune&lt;/a&gt; has blanketed his home state of South Dakota to talk up the legislation — where he also promised, in &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/watch/live/?ref=watch_permalink&amp;amp;v=775696638316110" target="_blank"&gt;a local TV interview this week&lt;/a&gt;, that its impact “will be more fully, you know, realized over time.” The most “immediate” win for voters, Thune said, is that the megabill will prevent a tax hike come 2026 since it extended dozens of soon-to-expire tax cuts the party enacted in 2017.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, Republicans are still fine tuning their messaging.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;At an industrial refrigeration manufacturing facility in Georgia on Thursday, Vance is expected to pitch the tax breaks in the megabill as a gift to working families. And a senior White House official, granted anonymity to discuss internal strategy, said part of the party's broader megabill rebrand will focus on reminding voters of the specific policy promises on which Trump campaigned and then followed through.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Step one is, you make them trust you and the way you make them trust you is by doing what you campaigned on,” said the official. “With the big, beautiful bill having passed, we fulfilled most of our signature promises from the campaign that people elected us for: no tax on tips, no tax on overtime pay, no tax on Social Security.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Vance will also use the Georgia trip to hammer Democratic Sen. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/34364" data-person-id="34364"&gt;Jon Ossoff&lt;/a&gt;, with Republicans viewing the incumbent’s seat as a top pick-up opportunity next year.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;William Martin, Vance’s communications director, &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/newsletters/playbook/2025/08/19/9-world-leaders-6-key-takeaways-and-1-big-promise-00513928" target="_blank"&gt;called it an “absolute disgrace” that Ossoff voted against the bill&lt;/a&gt; and “that’s something Vice President Vance will be sure to emphasize during his visit to Peachtree City.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Ossoff is already offering a pre-buttal of his own: “JD promised the new GOP would fight for working families,” he said in a statement. “Instead he's defunding hospitals, nursing homes, and Medicaid to cut taxes for the wealthy.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;While CBO found that middle-income households will see their resources grow as a result of the megabill, &lt;a href="https://subscriber.politicopro.com/article/2025/08/gop-megabill-will-mostly-benefit-the-wealthy-cbo-says-00504260" target="_blank"&gt;it’s the wealthiest 10 percent&lt;/a&gt; that will get the biggest bump.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Another hurdle for Republicans? They are trying to get voters to focus on the yet-to-be-fully-seen wins of the megabill while voters are distracted by other, more tangible issues: the fight over the release of the Jeffrey Epstein files, recent developments in the Russia-Ukraine conflict and a move by at least two states to redraw their congressional maps mid-decade.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Rep. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/227109" data-person-id="227109"&gt;Don Bacon&lt;/a&gt; of Nebraska, one of the few Republicans from a district won by former Vice President Kamala Harris in 2024, said he’s also getting an earful about efforts by the Office of Management and Budget to freeze federal funding for widely-used government programs.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Bacon suggested Trump’s new domestic policy law is taking a backseat at home these days: “I hear more about all the grant money that is frozen by OMB,” he said.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mia McCarthy and Jake Traylor contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>103</id>
            <title>Office of Management and Budget Director Russell Vought prepares to testify during an appropriations hearing on Capitol Hill, on June 4, 2025.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/20/trump-vought-pocket-rescissions-shutdown-00515278</link>
            <description>The White House is now within the window of attempting a contentious “pocket rescission” to cancel federal cash no matter what Congress says.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-20T03:45:00</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>11</id>
                <name>Katherine</name>
                <surname>Tully-McManus</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\47e90690-392b-402a-8045-61921e2bb232.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump’s budget director has talked about attempting the ultimate override of Congress’ funding prerogatives during the final 45 days of the fiscal year — and that time is now.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With six weeks left until Oct. 1, lawmakers are staring down a government shutdown deadline alongside the threat of a “pocket rescission,” a controversial White House tactic to cancel federal cash without the consent of Congress. It’s also a ploy that the government’s top watchdog, along with &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/20/pocket-rescissions-white-house-funding-trick-00410444" target="_blank"&gt;key lawmakers from both parties&lt;/a&gt;, say is illegal.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“The money evaporates at the end of the fiscal year,” White House budget chief Russ Vought said last month in defense of the gambit, adding it has “been used before.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers anticipate Trump will send Congress a formal rescissions request to claw back billions of dollars in federal funding as soon as lawmakers return from recess in September.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Already, the threat of the White House then unilaterally canceling the funding in October — regardless of Congress’ response to the request — is straining negotiations between Democrats and Republicans desperately trying to head off a shutdown with bipartisan negotiations, which &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/07/17/congress/russ-vought-appropriations-process-has-to-be-less-bipartisan-00459479" target="_blank"&gt;Vought is also actively seeking to undermine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“He is trying to throw a wrench in this by introducing or sending to us a second rescission bill — by trying to do pocket rescissions,” Delaware Sen. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/151823" data-person-id="151823"&gt;Chris Coons&lt;/a&gt;, the top Democrat on the appropriations panel that funds the military, said of Vought in an interview.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;It also would undoubtedly throw Republicans into another politically dicey balancing act of trying not to buck their president while answering to constituents who are feeling the effects of the administration’s mass gutting of widely used government programs.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Congress cleared an initial rescissions package of $9 billion in cuts to public broadcasting and foreign aid in July. The White House has stayed publicly mum on what sort of programming it would seek to slash next, but officials have previously signaled the &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/07/22/white-house-education-cuts-clawback-package-00468856" target="_blank"&gt;Department of Education will be the target of a second package&lt;/a&gt;, which could align with Trump’s controversial goal of eventually eliminating the agency altogether.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;As for the size of this upcoming clawbacks request, Republicans have mixed predictions. Last month, Speaker &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/242539" data-person-id="242539"&gt;Mike Johnson&lt;/a&gt; told members that a second package would be less than the $9 billion, but other GOP lawmakers said they expect to be asked to revoke much more money than that.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Under decades-old budget law, the White House is allowed to send Congress a rescissions request and then withhold the cash for 45 days while lawmakers consider whether to approve, reject or ignore the proposal. If lawmakers don’t pass the rescissions bill, the administration must spend the money as Congress intended. These were the conditions under which the administration transmitted its most recent plan.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Now, with less than 45 days before the current fiscal year comes to a close, top Trump administration officials argue the White House can send another rescissions package and then treat the funding as expired come midnight on Sept. 30 — regardless of congressional action.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;And if the White House moves forward with the plan, it could do more than just cause political headaches. It very likely would kick off a high-stakes legal battle over Congress’ funding power and whether a presidential administration must spend all of the money prescribed by law or whether the spending levels are simply “a ceiling,” as Vought has contended.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Government Accountability Office has said repeatedly that pocket rescissions are against the law and would “cede Congress’s power of the purse by allowing a president to, in effect, change the law by shortening the period of availability for fixed-period funds.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Vought has taken aim at the watchdog&lt;b&gt;,&lt;/b&gt; and Mark Paoletta, the Office of Management and Budget general counsel, piled on this month.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Trump Derangement Syndrome is on full display” at GAO, Paoletta &lt;a href="https://x.com/MarkPaoletta/status/1953518597164171585" target="_blank"&gt;said on social media&lt;/a&gt;, and “wrong on pocket rescissions.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Congress is well aware” that the law allows the maneuver, he added, pointing out that lawmakers did not bother heeding GAO’s urging 50 years ago to fix a loophole leaving the legality question open to interpretation.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Yet even some of the Republican lawmakers who are hungry for more chances to kill funding are wary of the Trump administration using the rescissions process to undermine Congress’ funding power under Article I of the Constitution.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Sen. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/192907" data-person-id="192907"&gt;Thom Tillis&lt;/a&gt; (R-N.C.), who reluctantly voted in support of the rescissions request last month, said he won’t support more clawback packages if the White House doesn’t provide account-by-account details of how the funding would be cut.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I'm just not going to aid and abet moving appropriations decisions over to the Article II branch,” Tillis said in an interview.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump “just happens to be a Republican,” Tillis continued, but “we could regret this, just as Democrats would, if they are tempted to do the same thing. That's why you’ve got to draw lines here institutionally.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Concerns about precedent, legality and political appetite are converging on the reality for members of both parties that Republicans can’t afford to alienate Democrats, whose votes they likely need to pass any government funding bill to avoid a shutdown next month.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Senate Majority Leader &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/51242" data-person-id="51242"&gt;John Thune&lt;/a&gt;, when asked about a second rescissions package, stressed he would prefer to handle any more cuts through the regular appropriations process. “My hope would be that that’s the way we deal with a lot of these issues,” he said.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Democrats hope so too, and they have warned that any Trump administration effort to claw back money already approved by Congress — “pocket” or otherwise — would undermine lawmakers’ ability to work across party lines to avoid a shutdown.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In remarks late last month alongside House Minority Leader &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/196306" data-person-id="196306"&gt;Hakeem Jeffries&lt;/a&gt; and his party’s senior appropriators, Senate Minority Leader &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/51231" data-person-id="51231"&gt;Chuck Schumer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/07/22/congress/schumer-jeffries-funding-message-shutdown-cliff-countdown-00468847" target="_blank"&gt;said Democrats&lt;/a&gt; would try to reach a compromise with Republicans despite GOP lawmakers’ approval of the latest $9 billion rescissions package.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But, he added, “Republicans are making it extremely difficult to do that … by talking about rescissions, pocket rescissions, impoundment — which would undo anything that we did in the budgets.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>104</id>
            <title>President Donald Trump alleges that Sen. Adam Schiff illicitly claimed his primary residence was Maryland for financial benefit.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/19/adam-schiff-forms-legal-defense-fund-00515046</link>
            <description>It is the latest chapter in Trump’s escalating effort to leverage the federal government against his political foes.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-19T14:27:25</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>10</id>
                <name>Hailey</name>
                <surname>Fuchs</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\1dd49475-6afe-4738-91c5-a62b543eb18f.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;California Democratic Sen. Adam Schiff, a longtime adversary of President Donald Trump, has &lt;a href="https://forms.irs.gov/app/pod/basicSearch/downloadFile?formId=134007&amp;amp;formType=e8871" target="_blank"&gt;formed a legal defense fund&lt;/a&gt;, amid the Justice Department probe into his finances.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Schiff, who led the first impeachment effort in the House against Trump and aided the congressional investigation into the Jan. 6 Capitol attack, has become a frequent target of the president in his second term. Earlier this summer, &lt;a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114857687712359546" target="_blank"&gt;Trump alleged in a post on Truth Social&lt;/a&gt; that the California Democrat “engaged in a sustained pattern of possible Mortgage Fraud” — an allegation Schiff vehemently denies.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“It’s clear that Donald Trump and his MAGA allies will continue weaponizing the justice process to attack Senator Schiff for holding this corrupt administration accountable,” Marisol Samayoa, a spokesperson for Schiff, said in a statement. “This fund will ensure he can fight back against these baseless smears while continuing to do his job.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump specifically alleges that Schiff illicitly claimed his primary residence was Maryland for financial benefit, and his administration has tapped Ed Martin — now pardon attorney and director of DOJ’s Weaponization Working Group — to oversee the matter.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Just a few months ago, Schiff vowed he would place a hold on Martin’s nomination to be U.S. Attorney in D.C., an effort to slow his confirmation prospects. Martin ultimately failed to gain enough support among the Senate GOP to secure his confirmation after Republican Sen. Thom Tillis said he would oppose Martin over his past defense of Jan. 6 rioters and his comments about the attack. Trump ultimately selected him for another post at the Department of Justice.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Schiff’s attorney, Preet Bharara — who has had his own confrontations with Trump as the top federal prosecutor in the Southern District of New York — has argued that Martin’s involvement into the Schiff probe represents “the very definition of weaponization of the justice process.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;FBI Director Kash Patel, who was once &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2020/02/20/kash-patel-odni-post-116546" target="_blank"&gt;a House Intelligence Committee staffer&lt;/a&gt; working to undermine the investigation into election interference, &lt;a href="https://x.com/BonginoReport/status/1955090263543574590" target="_blank"&gt;has also released materials&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/democratic-whistleblower-told-fbi-adam-schiff-approved-classified-leaks-target-trump" target="_blank"&gt;suggests the California Democrat supported leaking&lt;/a&gt; information during his time on the House Intelligence Committee to damage the president’s reputation. A spokesperson for Schiff has called the allegation “absolutely and categorically false” and “the latest in a series of defamatory attacks from the President and his allies.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The acrimony between Schiff and Trump dates back to Trump’s first term, when Schiff, then among former Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s top allies in th&lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2020/01/22/senate-impeachment-trial-opening-arguments-witnesses-102065" target="_blank"&gt;e House, served as the top prosecutor in the president’s first impeachment trial&lt;/a&gt;. The case centered around allegations of “abuse of power” and “obstruction of Congress” though the GOP-controlled &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2020/02/05/trump-impeachment-vote-110805" target="_blank"&gt;Senate eventually acquitted Trump&lt;/a&gt;. Schiff parlayed the celebrity brought on by that trial into a successful &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2023/07/13/trump-impeachment-schiff-raskin-00105955" target="_blank"&gt;Senate campaign in California&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump, meanwhile, has continued to criticize Schiff.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“They got this phony investigation going on, ‘Russia Russia Russia,” &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/shorts/GDegVibX0wE" target="_blank"&gt;he said at a press conference ahead of his Alaska meeting with Vladimir Putin last week&lt;/a&gt;. ”Totally phony, created by Adam Schiff, Shifty Schiff and Hillary Clinton and the whole group of ‘em. And it made it very dangerous for our country.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>105</id>
            <title>House Minority Whip Katherine Clark (D-Mass.) speaks during a press conference at the U.S. Capitol June 24, 2025.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/19/katherine-clark-israel-war-00514667</link>
            <description>Her statement comes after saying the “genocide and destruction” in Gaza needs to end.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-19T13:33:35</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>12</id>
                <name>Nicole</name>
                <surname>Markus</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\b886534e-657b-443c-9f30-c9638dd6ded3.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;House Minority Whip Katherine Clark (D-Mass.) said that she was not accusing the Israeli government of committing genocide in Gaza, despite saying at an event last week there was “genocide and destruction” in the war-torn strip.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Last week, while attending an event in my district, I repeated the word ‘genocide’ in response to a question. I want to be clear that I am not accusing Israel of genocide, ” she said in the statement to POLITICO on Tuesday. “We all need to work with urgency to bring the remaining hostages home, surge aid to Palestinians and oppose their involuntary relocation, remove Hamas from power, and end the war.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Clark’s statement was first reported by &lt;a href="https://www.jns.org/no-2-house-democrat-backtracks-comment-about-gaza-genocide/" target="_blank"&gt;the Jewish News Syndicate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Clark made her comments at an event hosted by a Quaker organization in her district last week, &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/15/katherine-clark-gaza-israel-00512112?nid=0000014f-704c-d54c-a1ff-fb6da68f0000&amp;amp;nname=massachusetts-playbook&amp;amp;nrid=df32436a-c7cc-41cf-af74-f924d3c1b9f6" target="_blank"&gt;POLITICO previously reported&lt;/a&gt;. At the event, she called on those in the audience to “take action in time to make a difference … whether that is stopping the starvation and genocide and destruction of Gaza” or other major political issues.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;A spokesperson at the time did not walk back the characterization but also said that her position on the fighting in the region hadn’t changed. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Though Democrats across the country have been critical of Israel’s ground offensive in Gaza, very few have called it a genocide. Clark is the second-highest ranking Democrat in the House and would have been one of the most senior members of the party to take that stance.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The war in Gaza has roiled the Democratic Party, as politicians and &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/14/2028-democrats-israel-gaza-litmus-test-00508934" target="_blank"&gt;potential 2028 candidates grapple&lt;/a&gt; with how to talk about the war and the humanitarian crisis in Gaza.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>106</id>
            <title>Sen. Chuck Grassley walks to a vote at the U.S. Capitol on June 16, 2025.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/19/senate-republicans-blue-slip-00513489</link>
            <description>Senators are fiercely protective of the longstanding precedent that gives them deference over who serves as U.S. attorneys and district court judges back home.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-19T03:45:00</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>10</id>
                <name>Hailey</name>
                <surname>Fuchs</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\d7db8653-e447-4b3e-9513-6ecbf3520534.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump last month tried to goad Sen. Chuck Grassley into ending the practice of giving deference to home-state senators in the judicial nominations process — a pressure campaign that quickly escalated into an all-out social media war on the 91-year-old Judiciary Committee chair.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Senator Grassley must step up,” Trump &lt;a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114938820270436889" target="_blank"&gt;said on Truth Social&lt;/a&gt;, noting that he got the Iowa Republican “re-elected to the U.S. Senate when he was down, by a lot.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;It didn’t work. Despite Trump’s threats to rally his base against Grassley, Senate Republicans rebuffed the attempts to get their colleague to give up on so-called blue slips, which allow members of the minority party power to effectively veto nominees for U.S. attorneys and district court judges who would serve their regions.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;It also doesn’t look like their position will change heading into the fall, either, as &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/07/29/congress/senate-nominations-rules-changes-00481796" target="_blank"&gt;Republicans have indicated&lt;/a&gt; they’ll seek a rules change to speed up the confirmation process for certain Trump nominees on the Senate floor but not at the committee level.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“As a practical matter, the Senate's not going to give up the blue slip,” said Sen. John Kennedy (R-La.), a member of the Judiciary Committee, in an interview. “So my appeal to the president is: please reconsider. Why do we want to have this fight for nothing?”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;It marks a rare instance where Hill Republicans have publicly broken with the president, underscoring how even Trump’s most loyal allies are willing to stand up to him when it comes to protecting their institution’s traditions — and their own ability to exert influence back home.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“The Senators have a real vested interest in what happens in their states,” said Mike Fragoso, a former chief counsel for nominations and constitutional law for the Senate Judiciary Committee. “At the end of the day, there’s probably very little support for what Trump wants within the conference."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Fragoso, who also served as chief counsel for former Senate Republican Leader Mitch McConnell of Kentucky, argued that even Republicans wary of crossing the president now have taken advantage of the blue slip policy when Democrats held power. He added that there are relatively few bench seats in solidly Democratic states that Trump could even fill now without consent from Democrats.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, said Fragoso, the blue slip’s elimination would just expose future seats in reliably red states like Florida and Texas to being filled with progressive judges by future Democratic administrations — and without the GOP getting much in return.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Grassley has also already made changes to the blue slip practice once, in 2017, when he announced he would move forward with circuit court nominees over home state senators’ objections. Although Judiciary chairs over the years had not always strictly followed that precedent, Grassley’s decision to consistently disregard it helped Trump see hundreds of judges confirmed during his first term in the White House.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;It also helped to facilitate the recent confirmation of Emil Bove to the Third Circuit Court of Appeals over objections from New Jersey’s Democratic senators, Cory Booker and Andy Kim. As a senior Justice Department official, Bove was accused of recommending the administration defy court orders that would interfere with Trump’s immigration agenda.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But circuit court judges are different from district court judges: They have jurisdiction that extends beyond a senator's state, while district judges and U.S. attorneys sit entirely within a given lawmaker’s home turf. And Republicans are finding themselves protective of maintaining control over these more localized positions as Trump is struggling to overcome Democratic roadblocks to confirming additional lower-level nominees.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Most recently, a court battle has broken out over Trump’s interim U.S. attorney for New Jersey, Alina Habba, after her temporary appointment expired and federal judges — not the president — installed a replacement. The Trump administration swiftly fired the court-selected pick and again appointed Habba, who Booker and Kim continue to oppose.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Senate Minority Leader Chuck Schumer is also leveraging the blue slip process by promising to withhold support for Jay Clayton to be the top federal prosecutor in the Southern District of New York — effectively blocking his confirmation.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump, losing patience, took to Truth Social in late July, calling in &lt;a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114938820270436889" target="_blank"&gt;his post for Grassley to have&lt;/a&gt; the “Courage” to “step up” and abandon the blue slip “SCAM” as Democratic “SLEAZEBAGS … have an ironclad stoppage of Great Republican Candidates.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;He went on to repost a slew of messages from various users of the platform backing up Trump’s calls for a blue slip boycott and directing their ire at the longest-serving senator. One person argued that Grassley’s abandonment of the blue slip practice would be a fitting “Swan song" for his political career, with another calling &lt;a href="https://truthsocial.com/@Chrissy3607/posts/114939054433580550" target="_blank"&gt;Grassley a “RINO&lt;/a&gt;” — or, a “Republican in Name Only.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Grassley, however, was unmoved.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I was offended by what the President said,” he said in opening remarks at a Judiciary Committee hearing the morning after Trump's initial post. “And I’m disappointed that it would result in personal insults.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Grassley’s colleagues defended him, too, with Senate Majority Leader John Thune saying there simply was &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/07/30/congress/trump-still-pressuring-grassley-00483116" target="_blank"&gt;no appetite to change&lt;/a&gt; the practice on Capitol Hill.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But while Republicans continue to make the argument for keeping blue slips for political preservation purposes, others insist there will be political consequences for not eschewing the process.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Rob Luther, who was a top administration official involved in judicial confirmations during Trump’s first term, said he has long advocated for getting rid of the blue slip policy.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The conservative base, Luther explained, will soon get agitated by the outstanding number of bench vacancies that cannot be filled because of obstacles imposed by Democrats. That will especially be the case, Luther said, because there are so few openings — only about 50 free seats, according to the U.S. courts website.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“The district court blue slip issue is going to come up this term because there just aren’t enough vacancies,” Luther said. “It’s in Republican interest to get rid of the blue slips because we really need to get some solid conservatives in these deep blue states, and it’s the only way it’s ever going to happen.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The blue slip practice also incentivizes senators to be uncooperative with their peers across the aisle, Luther said, recalling how there were significant vacancies on federal district courts during the first Trump administration because some progressive lawmakers from deep blue states were unwilling to make a deal on nominees.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Grassley seems to have anticipated this could become a liability for Republicans. Before he became the subject of Trump’s ire on the very subject, he began polling members of his committee to see if they’d support eliminating blue slips, Sen. Thom Tillis recently said on the Senate floor.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The North Carolina Republican — a member of the panel who is not seeking reelection — said he told Grassley that even if the policy were to be rescinded, he would continue to honor it anyway by opposing all relevant nominees who lacked support from their home state senators.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;That stance would likely result in nominees being reported unfavorably out of the Judiciary Committee, setting up additional procedural roadblocks on the Senate floor — a counterintuitive outcome if eliminating blue slips was designed to clear the way.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In an interview, Tillis also warned of what would happen if Republicans changed the rules and then lost control of the Senate to Democrats: “It just means that you will not have any control when the roles are reversed.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We can't bow to pressure because of legitimate frustration in the moment,” he continued. “I get President Trump is frustrated. But I also understand, as somebody who’s spent 10 years in this institution and 10 years on Judiciary, it would be a bad idea. And he would even regret it.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>107</id>
            <title>House Oversight Chair James Comer (R-Ky.) is seen after the House passed budget reconciliation legislation at the U.S. Capitol May 22, 2025.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/18/doj-turning-over-epstein-files-capitol-hill-00513606</link>
            <description>A House committee was forced to issue a subpoena to DOJ compelling the release of the materials.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-18T16:00:38</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>10</id>
                <name>Hailey</name>
                <surname>Fuchs</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\8c16987a-fa44-4314-824c-f1a4d91d03dc.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Congressional lawmakers will get their hands on a first tranche of Epstein files in the coming days.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;House Oversight Committee chair James Comer in a statement Monday said the Justice Department would start to turn over Jeffrey Epstein-related materials this Friday — less than two weeks after the Kentucky Republican transmitted a subpoena to the agency to demand access to documents connected to the deceased financier and sex offender.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Comer cautioned, however, that it could take a while for all the DOJ materials to come through.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Officials with the Department of Justice have informed us that the Department will begin to provide Epstein-related records to the Oversight Committee this week on Friday,” he said. “There are many records in DOJ’s custody, and it will take the Department time to produce all the records and ensure the identification of victims and any child sexual abuse material are redacted.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Speaking with reporters earlier in the day on Capitol Hill, Comer said his committee was “in constructive, productive conversations with the DOJ” about the release of further files in the Epstein case, ahead of the Aug. 19 deadline the committee included in its subpoena.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Still, the possibility that any materials are now forthcoming comes at a critical juncture for Democrats in their efforts to play up the controversy over the secretive nature of the Epstein files to undermine Republicans, particularly as the weeks count down to the end of the August recess.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Comer was compelled to issue the subpoena for the files last month when, during an otherwise routine Oversight subcommittee hearing, Democrats were able to get enough Republicans to take their side in a vote to force the action. It was a major victory for Democrats, who have been seeking to stoke divisions among the president's base over the matter, including by highlighting the administration’s lack of transparency.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump’s allies and supporters have long peddled conspiracy theories about what happened to Epstein, who died by suicide behind bars and has a long history of ties to powerful people — including Trump. Yet now the president and his inner circle have largely been trying to keep documents related to the charges against Epstein under wraps.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The issue has also roiled Republicans in Congress. GOP leadership has moved to quash efforts to force the release of materials in the Epstein matter and sent lawmakers back to their districts early amid mounting pressure to allow a vote on releasing the materials.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Members of both parties have made clear they plan to pick up where they left off in this fight when the House returns early next month, starting with a forcing a vote on the House floor on a resolution from Reps. Thomas Massie (R-Ky.) and Ro Khanna (D-Calif.) calling for the files’ unsealing.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;For his part, Comer is now proceeding with a probe of his own through the Oversight Committee. Last month, when Oversight subcommittee Democrats seemingly surprised colleagues by having enough votes to subpoena Epstein case materials, it opened up something of an impromptu, subpoena vote free-for-all, culminating in demands that more than half a dozen public officials testify.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;One of those officials brought in to be interviewed behind closed doors was Trump’s former attorney general, Bill Barr, who came to Capitol Hill to speak with members and staff on Monday.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“What Attorney General Barr testified in there was that he never had conversations with President Trump pertaining to a client list, he didn’t know anything about a client list,” Comer told reporters. “He said that he had never seen anything that would implicate President Trump in any of this.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Asked whether the committee was interested in interviewing additional witnesses like Alex Acosta — Trump’s former Labor secretary who oversaw Epstein’s plea agreement as a U.S. attorney in Florida — Comer said the committee would bring in any additional individuals who could add information to the investigation.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;A DOJ spokesperson declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Erica Orden contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>108</id>
            <title>During a speech Wednesday, President Donald Trump repeatedly floated circumventing Congress to maintain his hold over Washington's law enforcement.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/13/trump-dc-police-congress-00507359</link>
            <description>The president must secure congressional approval to extend the 30-day federal takeover.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-13T13:00:41</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>13</id>
                <name>Giselle</name>
                <surname>Ruhiyyih</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\c296fa97-a741-4cd8-b22a-4f04569b9e4c.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump on Wednesday suggested that he could avoid congressional approval to extend his 30-day federal takeover of Washington’s police, amid his efforts to wrest control of the capital’s law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump this week &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/11/trump-dc-police-federal-control-00502708" target="_blank"&gt;invoked the Home Rule Act&lt;/a&gt;, effectively handing the executive branch control over Washington’s police for up to 30 days. Beyond that, Trump would have to go through Congress for an extension authorization.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But during his speech announcing the 2025 Kennedy Center honorees on Wednesday, Trump repeatedly floated circumventing Congress to maintain his hold over the city’s law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“If it's a national emergency we can do it without Congress, but we expect to be before Congress very quickly,” Trump said.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump appeared to be banking on the support of congressional Republicans to push through any attempt to extend the 30 day takeover — but maintained that if lawmakers failed to approve the extension, he would go forward with the move on his own by declaring a national emergency.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I don't want to call a national emergency,” Trump said, before adding, “If I have to, I will.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump also announced that he was working with congressional Republicans to put forward a crime bill initially targeted at Washington but intended as a “beacon” for other Democratic cities such as New York, Chicago and Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We're going to need a crime bill that we're going to be putting in, and it's going to pertain initially to D.C.,” Trump said. “We're going to be asking for extensions on that, long-term extensions, because you can't have 30 days.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;California already felt the repercussions of the Trump administration’s targeting earlier this summer, when the president deployed the National Guard to help quell protests against immigration detention sweeps in Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump on Monday announced that he was taking control over Washington’s police force and deploying the National Guard to patrol the city’s streets. Citing a rise in violent crime — which local leaders have disputed, pointing to statistics showing the city hitting a 30-year low last year — Trump declared that Monday was “&lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/articles/2025/08/its-liberation-day-in-washington-d-c/" target="_blank"&gt;Liberation Day&lt;/a&gt;” for the city, and invoked a never-been-used statute of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act allowing the president to take control over the local police in cases of emergency.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;So far, D.C. leadership has been playing nice with the president, with Mayor Muriel Bowser calling the move “unsettling and unprecedented” — but still &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/11/dc-mayor-trump-police-order-unsettling-unprecedented-00504209" target="_blank"&gt;saying the city&lt;/a&gt; would comply with Trump’s order.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The president on Wednesday added that he would be “going to Congress for a relatively small amount of money” to “fix up” the nation’s capital, including fixing potholes and getting rid of medians in the city’s roads.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Asked about the prospect of D.C. statehood, which the city’s leaders have long pushed for without success, Trump called the efforts “ridiculous” and “unacceptable,” saying the overwhelmingly blue city would “pick up two senators, and that's not going to happen.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>109</id>
            <title>A spokesperson said Eleanor Holmes Norton's "top priority is to ensure that home rule and D.C. residents are protected."</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/13/eleanor-holmes-norton-trump-dc-00506273</link>
            <description>The 88-year-old congressional delegate has mounted a back-seat response to the most serious federal threat to the city’s government in 30 years.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-13T08:00:00</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>14</id>
                <name>Nicholas</name>
                <surname>Wu</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\7f903a95-ede0-4b65-a0e9-6627ac9a7d90.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Washington's locally elected government is under attack from President Donald Trump and congressional Republicans. But the capital city's self-proclaimed "warrior on the Hill" is nowhere to be seen on the front lines.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Eleanor Holmes Norton, the District of Columbia’s nonvoting House delegate, issued a &lt;a href="https://norton.house.gov/media/press-releases/norton-statement-after-president-trump-federalizes-dc-police-and-activates-dc" target="_blank"&gt;written statement&lt;/a&gt; Monday after Trump seized control of the city's police force and moved to send in National Guard troops, calling it "counterproductive," a "historic assault on D.C. home rule" and "more evidence of the urgent need to pass my D.C. statehood bill."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But Norton — who has represented the city in the House since 1991 — has not been seen in public or otherwise interacted with the media since, even as other elected Democrats stepped forward to defend Washington’s autonomy against Trump's aggressive new actions.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Washington Mayor Muriel Bowser held an hourlong news conference Monday afternoon in which she was flanked by city public safety officials, but not Norton. Her name was also missing from a joint statement released by members of Congress representing Washington's suburbs that slammed the police takeover as a “soft launch of authoritarianism.” Several of those lawmakers have since given interviews to POLITICO and other outlets.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries said Tuesday afternoon he had yet to speak to Norton about a response to Trump's moves, which were announced Monday morning. The New York Democrat said he hoped to have that conversation later in the day.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Norton did not accept an interview request made through a spokesperson, who declined to identify any other interviews or public appearances she has made since Trump escalated his threats against the city late last week.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The spokesperson, Sharon Eliza Nichols, said in a statement that Norton has been “working diligently with Mayor Bowser, city officials and her colleagues discussing how to support the District’s response and prevent further federal incursions against D.C.'s right to handle its own affairs.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Congresswoman Norton has proven her dedication to the people of D.C.,” the statement continued. “She understands the unprecedented circumstances the District is in, and her top priority is to ensure that home rule and D.C. residents are protected."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Norton’s back-seat response to the most serious federal threat to the city's government in 30 years is out of step with her one-time reputation as a fierce defender of local prerogatives in the face of meddling by federal authorities. Her campaign website still &lt;a href="https://www.eleanorfordc.com/" target="_blank"&gt;promotes the “warrior” moniker&lt;/a&gt; she has used for decades to reflect her often fiery battles with Republicans.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But she is facing &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2025/07/07/capitol-hill-gerontocracy-eleanor-holmes-norton-dianne-feinstein-joe-biden-00437318" target="_blank"&gt;mounting questions&lt;/a&gt; about her plans to seek a 19th term next year as fellow Democrats privately voice concerns about her fading presence in the House. She has twice told reporters she intends to run again in 2026, but in both instances her staff subsequently said &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/10/congress/eleanor-holmes-norton-reelection-00397248" target="_blank"&gt;she is undecided&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;A campaign spokesperson did not respond to a request for an update on her reelection plans.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;A person granted anonymity to describe Norton's thinking said her low-key approach to the joint statement was in keeping with the more conciliatory approach Bowser and other city officials have taken with Trump in his second term. Norton, the person said, does not want to provoke Trump into escalating his attacks on the D.C. government.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Bowser, however, has appeared on camera multiple times since Trump’s announcement to take questions and defend the city’s public safety efforts, as have some D.C. Council members.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The person said Norton wasn’t invited or notified by the mayor’s office about Bowser's news conference. Another person granted anonymity to comment on the sensitive situation said it was not standard practice to invite federal officials such as Norton to mayoral news conferences. The mayor’s office declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Norton was invited to join the joint statement from the Washington-area House delegation but ultimately did not sign on for strategic reasons, the person said.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Behind the scenes, Norton has been involved in marshalling a response to Trump's actions beyond her Monday statement. Nichols said she has been “actively reaching out to civic associations and other groups of D.C. residents” and helped organize a Monday evening conference call with Bowser and members of the Congressional Black Caucus.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Norton helped open the conversation, according to four people granted anonymity to discuss the private call, where the lawmakers discussed recent steps taken by the city to address crime.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The CBC occupies a special place in the fight for D.C. voting rights and political autonomy. The group played a key role in securing passage of the Home Rule Act in 1973, creating the city's locally elected government — one of the caucus’s first major legislative victories following its founding in 1969.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;CBC Chair Yvette Clarke (D-N.Y.) said in a Tuesday statement that the group will "continue fighting to protect D.C.’s right to self-governance and we urge all Americans to recognize this for what it is: a test run for broader authoritarian overreach."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"The stakes are high not just for Washington, D.C., but for the future of democracy in every corner of this country,” Clarke continued.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Most elected Democrats are loath to publicly criticize Norton given her long record of fighting for the city — including during the mid-1990s, when Congress imposed a financial control board to manage most city affairs. Norton was instrumental in pushing through legislation that recalibrated the city's relationship with Congress and is widely seen as setting the stage for its economic rebirth and population growth over the following two decades.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Many also believe that Trump would have gone after the District regardless of what its elected officials said or did in the lead-up to his announcements Monday. But others contend that, without an actual vote in Congress, the D.C. delegate's foremost responsibility is to rally support for the city and make the case for its autonomy to the American public.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Kinney Zalesne, a former DNC official who is running against Norton, said in a Tuesday interview that "there's an opportunity here for the D.C. delegate to be a loud and consistent and powerful and unrelenting voice for D.C. to Congress, to the administration and to the rest of the nation.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"One or two statements" did not meet that standard, she said: “We need to tell the truth about this federal overreach — that it's unnecessary, inappropriate and potentially illegal.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Norton's Democratic colleagues on Capitol Hill, meanwhile, voiced support — even as some said they had not spoken to her amid this moment of crisis.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I'm going to continue to support her and D.C., because many of my constituents work in D.C.,” said Rep. Suhas Subramanyam, who represents a district in the Virginia suburbs. “I know people have brought up the issue of her ability to serve. … I haven't had a problem serving with her.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Jeffries, speaking to reporters Tuesday in Illinois, said "I have not had a conversation with Delegate Norton as of yet, but have been in communication with Mayor Bowser [and] indicated that we are going to strongly support her efforts to defend the sovereignty and integrity of the District of Columbia."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"I look forward to connecting with her at some point later on today," he added later.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Shia Kapos contributed to this report from Springfield, Illinois.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>110</id>
            <title>Sen. Chris Murphy speaks with a reporter on his way to a vote at the U.S. Capitol on June 17, 2025.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/13/chris-murphy-senate-funding-boycott-trump-protest-00505880</link>
            <description>The politically ambitious Connecticut Democrat is walking away from bipartisan government funding negotiations as his party clamors for a seat at the table.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-13T03:45:00</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>3</id>
                <name>Jennifer</name>
                <surname>Scholtes</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\a2ed6051-4063-4f2e-907f-1687931b0ecb.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Chris Murphy has been warning for months that voters want Democrats to fight. This summer, the Connecticut senator is picking a battle that puts him at odds with his Democratic colleagues.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Murphy has made surprising moves over the last month to protest bipartisan government funding talks as a member of the Appropriations Committee, demonstrating his vision of what opposition to President Donald Trump should look like and further stoking speculation about his own presidential ambitions.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The third-term senator said in a recent interview that Trump "doesn't give a fuck what we write” into spending legislation. And so he sees no reason to participate in the drafting of funding bills if the president is going to keep withholding billions of dollars Congress already approved and goading Republican senators to claw back more.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Every single day, there's new evidence that our democracy is falling, and you've got to take stands. You have to take fights,” Murphy explained. “I just worry — every time that we go along with these appropriations bills, we're putting a bipartisan veneer of endorsement on an illegal process that's ultimately part of his campaign to destroy our democracy.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;As the top Democrat on the appropriations panel that funds the Department of Homeland Security, Murphy occupies a role that has historically demanded across-the-aisle collaboration. But in recent weeks, he opposed all spending measures advanced during Senate Appropriations Committee markups for which he was present, challenged his Republican counterpart on the DHS funding bill and voted “no” on the Senate’s first bipartisan funding package of the year.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I’m nothing if not consistent. I don’t like the position I’m in,” Murphy said. “It’s lonely. 28-to-1 votes are lonely.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;So far, Murphy isn’t slamming his colleagues for embracing bipartisan negotiations, and his peers aren’t directly criticizing his approach. But they aren’t exactly praising him either.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“He has the right to his opinion," said the top Democratic appropriator in the Senate, Patty Murray of Washington. "And I just have the opinion that the more we can do to get bills done, the better chance we have of getting better things for our country.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Sen. Brian Schatz of Hawaii, one of Murphy’s friends and another senior member of the Appropriations Committee, said Democrats have a duty to at least attempt to strike a cross-party compromise on federal spending ahead of the Sept. 30 shutdown deadline.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I’m not his spokesperson,” said Schatz, who is in line to be the chamber’s Democratic whip in the next Congress. “So all I can say is: We've been demanding a bipartisan process. So when there's a step in that direction, I think it’s our obligation to try to be constructive.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;While Murphy has never been a moderate, he has grown rapidly into a liberal firebrand in recent years. Once best known on Capitol Hill for his advocacy for gun control and his foreign policy expertise, he's now a frequent anti-Trump voice on cable news shows and has waded into controversial social topics like &lt;a href="https://www.chrismurphyct.com/p/the-reason-to-care-about-the-plight" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;the nation’s “male identity” crisis&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But Murphy’s latest political stand against Trump comes as his name is floated for a bigger-stage battle against Republicans — this time as a presidential contender in 2028.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;If the 52-year-old senator seeks the Democratic nomination in three years, his protest of government funding bills could help differentiate him as a candidate who fought the Trump administration with more than just verbal criticism.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“It does fit, right? These are strategies that would make sense if he's interested in a national platform and to run for office like president,” said Hans Noel, a Georgetown University professor who studies presidential nominations.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“There's some appeal to a lot of voters — of fighting — especially at the national stage, where he doesn't have to worry about winning over allies for legislative progress,” Noel continued. “Murphy has been somebody who’s been talking on a national stage for a long time. It’s not completely new. But he’s somebody who’s got that kind of appeal.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;This past week, Murphy spent his birthday at an event with progressives in Arizona, where he talked broadly about the need for Democrats to balance opposition with real policy commitments: “We can’t just be against Donald Trump. We’ve got to give people a vision of something different.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Since Trump’s election last November, Murphy has grown a beard, announced the end of his 17-year marriage and sparked rumors about romantic ties to a prominent Democratic strategist. In April, he hosted a town hall back in rural North Carolina — more than 500 miles from his blue home state. Then this summer, he &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/02/murphy-anti-trump-pac-2026-00378509" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;launched a PAC&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aimed at taking on Trump and Republicans in Congress.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Murphy hasn’t always resisted negotiations with Republicans. In 2022, after a gunman left 21 people dead inside a Texas elementary school, he undertook weeks of painstaking talks that resulted in the first significant federal gun-control legislation in two decades. It was the culmination of a nearly decade-long fight for Murphy, who represented Sandy Hook Elementary School in the House at the time of that devastating 2012 shooting.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;His next foray into bipartisan talks did not have a happy ending. Last year he scrupulously crafted the high-profile bipartisan border deal with Oklahoma Republican Sen. James Lankford, in an attempt to enact Congress’ first major immigration overhaul in more than three decades. Then Trump &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/02/05/border-bill-trump-00139584" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;chilled Republican support&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for the bill.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;To Murphy, it signaled that Republicans couldn’t be trusted to be good-faith actors in negotiations to fund the government: “I think that drama was early proof that they're never going to cross him,” he said of Republicans’ loyalty to Trump.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;This belief was further cemented when Murphy’s GOP colleagues cleared Trump’s $9 billion rescission request last month targeting public broadcasting and foreign aid.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“They can say that they're going to honor the words on the page,” Murphy said. Yet if Trump “decides to ignore the law,” he continued, “I just don't think that my Republican colleagues are going to really fight to protect it.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Democratic leadership’s interest in engaging in bipartisan funding negotiations, from which Murphy is abstaining, is a relatively new development. Just a month ago, Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer penned a lengthy “dear colleague” letter insinuating that his members should cut off cross-party talks if Republicans accepted the White House’s rescissions package.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Nine days later, Senate Republicans banded together to pass that bill. And five days after that, &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/07/22/congress/schumer-jeffries-funding-message-shutdown-cliff-countdown-00468847" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Schumer stood with his House counterpart&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries, to announce that Democrats still “want to pursue a bipartisan, bicameral appropriations process.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;It has left Murphy as the lone Democratic appropriator continually opposing the funding bills his colleagues are trying to advance, even as he readily admits it’s not the substance of the spending measures he’s against.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“The bills themselves are good, bipartisan bills,” said Murphy. “It's just — I don't believe that anything in there is actually going to be implemented.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;This is the case Murphy said he wants to get through to Sen. Katie Britt, the Alabama Republican who chairs the Homeland Security appropriations panel opposite Murphy. The two lawmakers were &lt;a href="https://x.com/ScottButtram/status/1946208084889608605" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;seen last month in a heated exchange&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in the well of the Senate floor after passage of the clawback request. Britt described the conversation, captured by C-SPAN cameras, as “a spirited dialogue,” vowing: “I’ll continue to work in good faith, as I always have.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Murphy, however, said negotiations on the DHS funding bill will be meaningless if Trump and Republicans are going to undermine the spending directives when the measure becomes law. “We had an animated discussion,” Murphy said of his talk with Britt. “Obviously it's hard to write a bill when the administration is going to stab you in the back as soon as you write it, especially in a space as difficult as immigration and DHS.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;He pointed to specific examples of how Trump has already undermined appropriators, including the president’s efforts to fund the controversial “Alligator Alcatraz” immigration detention center in Florida by diverting money Congress appropriated for “humane” alternatives to detainment.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“And you know,” Murphy continued, “he's going to use the money in this budget to treat immigrants like animals.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Jordain Carney, Katherine Tully-McManus and Cassandra Dumay contributed to this report.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>111</id>
            <title>House Oversight Chair James Comer has summoned D.C. officials to testify on what he calls their “radical, soft-on-crime agenda.”</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/11/dc-crime-congress-house-gop-00504032</link>
            <description>But it will be difficult to get actual legislation to the president’s desk.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-11T15:16:07</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>10</id>
                <name>Hailey</name>
                <surname>Fuchs</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\56b78885-7711-4aa0-b149-16edfb7202d4.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;House Republicans moved quickly Monday to follow President Donald Trump’s lead as he took unprecedented action to target Washington’s locally elected government — further heightening the GOP’s scrutiny of the capital city and its Democratic elected leaders.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Oversight Chair James Comer (R-Ky.) said he would haul Mayor Muriel Bowser, Council Chair Phil Mendelson and Attorney General Brian Schwalb to Capitol Hill next month for a hearing. The public grilling is likely to come as Trump’s &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/11/trump-dc-police-federal-control-00502708" target="_blank"&gt;takeover of Washington’s Metropolitan Police Department&lt;/a&gt; approaches a 30-day expiration date, requiring congressional action to continue.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“For years, the D.C. Council’s radical, soft-on-crime agenda has emboldened criminals and put public safety at risk in our nation’s capital,” Comer said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;His voice was one of many in the GOP who hailed Trump’s moves Monday to seize control of the D.C. police force and deploy the National Guard in the capital. Speaker Mike Johnson, for instance, said in a post on X that “House Republicans support this effort to CLEAN UP Washington, END the crime wave, and RESTORE the beauty of the greatest capital in the world.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;While violent crime &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-dc/pr/violent-crime-dc-hits-30-year-low" target="_blank"&gt;reached a 30-year low&lt;/a&gt; in the city last year, Republicans argue Washington is unsafe and poorly governed. A spate of carjackings and several other recent high-profile incidents have captured GOP attention on Capitol Hill, including the murder of an intern for Rep. Ron Estes (R-Kan.) and the &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/05/trump-administration-staffer-known-as-big-balls-assaulted-in-dc-00494990" target="_blank"&gt;assault last week of a Trump administration staffer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Comer in his statement said his panel would also be “advancing legislative solutions to protect Americans in their capital city.” During a news conference Monday, Trump called for the reimposition of cash bail, which has been largely abolished in D.C. for more than 30 years, while U.S. Attorney Jeanine Pirro called for congressional action to overturn “absurd” juvenile justice laws that she said provided too much leniency for young offenders.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;An Oversight Committee spokesperson said the panel would work to advance legislation introduced by Rep. Byron Donalds (R-Fla.) that would limit “youth offender status” to those 18 years old or younger. Currently, those 24 or younger can qualify as youth offenders in the District.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The legislation from Donalds would also require the D.C. attorney general to publicly track juvenile crime in the city and bar the locally elected D.C. Council from passing provisions to change its sentencing rules.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The bill passed the House last year in a bipartisan 225-181 vote but did not advance in the Senate, which was then controlled by Democrats. The spokesperson said the committee was considering additional legislation but did not provide details. Rep. Elise Stefanik (R-N.Y.), a member of GOP leadership, is also working on legislation to reverse no-cash-bail policies nationwide.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;It’s unclear how soon any D.C.-related legislation might hit the House floor. Lawmakers are now on their extended summer recess, and House GOP leaders expect the Oversight Committee to start advancing a slate of bills in September. That means floor action could be delayed until later in the fall, depending on how quickly the panel works through its process, according to three people granted anonymity to discuss internal planning.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;House Republicans may be forced to deal with city-related matters sooner, however. Trump’s executive action Monday commandeering the Metropolitan Police started a 30-day clock for presidential control, as provided for in the 52-year-old law establishing the city’s locally elected government.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Extending Trump’s control of the department would require congressional action — forcing the White House and GOP congressional leaders to make a decision as they also deal with messy internal fights over whether to force the release of more documents related to the Jeffrey Epstein case and a politically explosive congressional stock trading ban.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In a letter sent to the Hill Monday informing of the police takeover, Trump said he would retain control “until I have determined, in consultation with the Attorney General, that the emergency has ended or for the maximum period permitted” under federal law.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump made no mention of seeking extended control of the department at his news conference Monday morning, where he was flanked by Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth, Attorney General Pam Bondi and other administration officials. He instead called on lawmakers to address the District’s longstanding bail policy, which allows criminal suspects to be released pending trial without putting up any money.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We’re gonna change no cash bail, we’re gonna change the statute and get rid of some of the other things,” Trump said. “And we’ll count on the Republicans in Congress and Senate to vote, we have the majority, so we’ll vote. We don’t have a big majority, but we’ve gotten everything, including the great Big Beautiful Bill.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Democrats, meanwhile, sharply objected to Trump’s moves in social media posts Monday, with House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries saying Trump has “no basis to take over the local police department” and “zero credibility on the issue of law and order.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Rep. Jamie Raskin (D-Md.) said he would introduce legislation that would immediately end Trump’s police takeover. He called it a “phony, manufactured crisis” and recalled Trump’s actions dealing with the Jan. 6, 2021, attack on the Capitol — where a mob of his supporters assaulted police and were later pardoned.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"This is plainly ridiculous," he said in an interview. "There are certainly cases that justify the deployment of the National Guard in Washington. One of them was Jan. 6, 2021 where Republican and Democratic leaders on the Hill were begging President Trump to activate the National Guard, and he did nothing for hours."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Another Democrat from the Washington region, Virginia Rep. Suhas Subramanyam, said Trump was "trying to distract people from the fact that his policies have been unpopular and a complete failure." He said he would "against any plan that has National Guard going into D.C. when it's not necessary."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;While Republicans can likely push D.C.-related bills through the House on party lines, Democrats in the Senate could use the filibuster to keep them from reaching Trump’s desk. Vaulting that obstacle would require a 60-vote majority, and it’s unlikely that Democrats — who have long championed political autonomy for the District’s largely Democratic populace — would join their Republican colleagues en masse. But it could force some vulnerable Senate Democrats into tough votes over crime and safety ahead of midterm elections.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Asked about potential legislation, a spokesperson for Senate Minority Leader Chuck Schumer said Monday that “all options are on the table to fight back this historic overreach.” Schumer himself said on social media Monday that the executive actions are a “political ploy and attempted distraction from Trump’s other scandals.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Nicholas Wu and Calen Razor contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;CORRECTION: An earlier version of this story misidentified Rep. Jamie Raskin's party. He is a Democrat.</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>112</id>
            <title>A member of the National Guard patrols the area outside of the U.S. Capitol in Washington on Feb. 10, 2021.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/11/dc-law-enforcement-national-guard-deployment-00502896</link>
            <description>The capital is already subject to significant federal control — and Trump is invoking his emergency powers to solidify it.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-11T11:13:02</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>4</id>
                <name>Kyle</name>
                <surname>Cheney</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\c129d6be-392f-4a5a-8bea-a1882da1e9bc.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump’s attempt to &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/11/trump-dc-police-federal-control-00502708" target="_blank"&gt;take over law enforcement&lt;/a&gt; in Washington, D.C., is once again testing the bounds of his authority to militarize a major U.S. city.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The capital, unlike other cities, is already subject to significant federal control — and Trump is invoking his emergency powers to solidify it. But the intersection of complicated laws and rules about the use of the military for domestic law enforcement, the deployment of federal agents to the streets of D.C. and the city’s own crime-fighting policies may still prompt legal uncertainty — and inevitable challenges.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what Trump can — and cannot — do:&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h4 class="story-text__heading-large"&gt;Trump said he’s taking control of the D.C. police. Can he do that?&lt;/h4&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Yes, with limits. The &lt;a href="https://dccouncil.gov/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Home-Rule-Act-2018-for-printing-9-13-182.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Home Rule Act&lt;/a&gt; gives him the power to use the D.C. police force for “federal purposes” if he determines that there are “special conditions of an emergency nature.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;He can use the D.C. police for up to 48 hours, or for up to 30 days if he sends a special message to the leaders of certain congressional committees.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;To use the D.C. police for longer than 30 days, he would need authorization from Congress.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In an order Monday, Trump said the D.C. police force under his control would protect federal buildings and national monuments, typically a function of federal law enforcement agencies.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;District of Columbia Attorney General Brian Schwalb called Trump's actions "&lt;a href="https://x.com/DCAttorneyGen/status/1954936123731652926" target="_blank"&gt;unprecedented, unnecessary, and unlawful&lt;/a&gt;." Schwalb said there is "no crime emergency" in the district that would justify the takeover of the police force. Violent crime in the district, he said, is at a 30-year low.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h4 class="story-text__heading-large"&gt;Trump also said he’s deploying National Guard troops to D.C. Can he do that?&lt;/h4&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Yes. Trump has more authority over the D.C. National Guard than he has over the guards of the 50 states. Governors control the state guards (although the president can federalize the state guards in an emergency or for use in combat operations). The District of Columbia, of course, has no governor, and the D.C. guard is not controlled by the mayor. Rather, the D.C. guard is always under the direct control of the president.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://static.politico.com/21/9f/9085eb524e51b3d3348b7eb3ba80/white-house-82728.jpg" alt="President Donald Trump, flanked by members of his administration, holds a press briefing in the James S. Brady Press Briefing Room at the White House, on Aug. 11, 2025." data-portal-copyright="Francis Chung/POLITICO" data-has-syndication-rights="0" data-license-id="" data-licensor-name="AP" data-title="President Donald Trump, flanked by members of his administration, holds a press briefing in the James S. Brady Press Briefing Room at the White House, on Aug. 11, 2025."/&gt;&lt;h4 class="story-text__heading-large"&gt;Aren’t there limits on using the military for domestic law enforcement?&lt;/h4&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Yes, but those limits might not apply to the D.C. National Guard.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;A federal law passed in 1878, &lt;a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/18/1385" target="_blank"&gt;the Posse Comitatus Act&lt;/a&gt;, bars the use of the U.S. military for civilian law enforcement except when authorized by the Constitution or another provision of federal law.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration is currently on trial in Los Angeles over its deployment of the California guard in June to quell &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/07/newsom-national-guard-los-angeles-00393526" target="_blank"&gt;immigration-related protests&lt;/a&gt; in that city. That trial will test whether a federal judge believes Trump’s deployment ran afoul of that 1878 law and must be rescinded.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But the legality of using the guard in D.C. may be different. Presidential use of the D.C. guard has rarely faced legal resistance because it has typically happened in cooperation with D.C. leaders. And the Justice Department has long maintained that the D.C. guard, unlike the other guards, can be used for ordinary law enforcement without violating Posse Comitatus. A 1989 &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/file/151081/dl?inline" target="_blank"&gt;legal opinion&lt;/a&gt; from the department’s Office of Legal Counsel found that President George H.W. Bush could use the D.C. guard to carry out law enforcement missions in D.C. as part of the so-called war on drugs.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;If Trump’s deployment of the D.C. guard is challenged in court, a judge would almost certainly take note of the OLC opinion, but would not be bound to follow it.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h4 class="story-text__heading-large"&gt;Does Trump have the power to “federalize” D.C.?&lt;/h4&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump cannot singlehandedly wrest control of the district’s government.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Constitution grants Congress the power to “&lt;a href="https://constitution.congress.gov/browse/essay/artI-S8-C17-1-2/ALDE_00001080/" target="_blank"&gt;exercise exclusive legislation&lt;/a&gt;” over the “seat of government” of the United States. In 1973, with the passage of the Home Rule Act, Congress created the local D.C. government that still exists to this day.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Under the act, D.C. has significant control of day-to-day local affairs. But the federal government — including federal law enforcement agencies such as the U.S. Capitol Police and the U.S. Park Police — retain control over federal land and property. And Congress has the final say on local D.C. policies: The Home Rule Act allows Congress to effectively veto any legislation passed by the D.C. Council.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The president alone has no authority to “federalize” the D.C. government; he would need Congress to amend the Home Rule Act.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h4 class="story-text__heading-large"&gt;Has Trump sent federal authorities into D.C. before?&lt;/h4&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Yes, Trump has tested the boundaries of his ability to use federal agents and the National Guard in Washington.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump has clear control and authority over tens of thousands of federal law enforcement officers who work in the area for federal agencies, including the FBI, the Marshals Service, the Secret Service, the Park Police and others. Trump deployed many of those agencies in June 2020 to clear Black Lives Matter protesters from Lafayette Park, across from the White House.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump also faced scrutiny for his inaction on Jan. 6, 2021 — as a mob of his supporters attacked the Capitol — when it came to ensuring the National Guard was racing to assist besieged lawmakers. Though Trump aides said he previously authorized them to deploy the National Guard as necessary, witnesses said Trump made no efforts to contact his military leadership during the chaos, even as his then-vice president, Mike Pence, was urgently making calls to ensure a federal response.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump on Monday also encouraged D.C. law enforcement officers to hit back “hard” if instigators spit at them and get in their faces. But Trump also pardoned hundreds of people who attacked and injured those very same officers on Jan. 6, sometimes with weapons, and suggested his supporters’ actions were “minor.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>113</id>
            <title>Sen. Mike Rounds (R-S.D.) is seen during a series of votes on a budget reconciliation bill for President Trump's legislative agenda at the U.S. Capitol June 30, 2025. (Francis Chung/POLITICO via AP Images)</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/11/another-megabill-senate-republicans-have-their-doubts-00499987</link>
            <description>The White House has yet to articulate its vision for a second, or third, reconciliation package.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-11T03:45:00</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>15</id>
                <name>Mia</name>
                <surname>McCarthy</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\7d657a32-1df4-4d9a-a2a6-3377ce30842b.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;House Republicans are pushing for a second megabill. The Senate GOP’s not so sure.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;After a grueling ordeal to get President Donald Trump’s “big, beautiful bill” signed into law last month, Speaker Mike Johnson and other leaders are already talking about crafting at least one more domestic policy package that can pass along party lines in the Senate.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;A White House official, granted anonymity to share details about private conversations, said another filibuster-skirting reconciliation bill is under discussion. The conservative Republican Study Committee has launched a “Reconciliation 2.0” working group and is hosting staff briefings throughout the summer recess to begin generating recommendations for follow-up legislation.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;And Senate Finance Committee Chair Mike Crapo (R-Idaho) said he’s open to considering as many as 200 tax proposals from his members that were ultimately not included in the first megabill.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But most senators have questions about what could go into another reconciliation package — and they’re casting doubts on whether it’s even politically possible to do this all over again.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“You have to have a reason to do it,” said Sen. Mike Rounds (R-S.D.). “It's not easy to do, so you have to have a purpose for doing it in the first place.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;That unifying purpose for Republicans the first time around was a desire to deliver Trump a major legislative victory early in his second term and prevent a tax hike that they feared would weaken the economy. Republican leaders’ decision to throw in a debt limit extension through 2026 as Treasury warned the nation would soon exceed its borrowing authority added a do-or-die incentive.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Without the pressure, I don’t see how you get it done,” said one Republican senator, granted anonymity to speak freely, about prospects for passing a second reconciliation bill without an existential impetus for action. “I don’t think I see what the pressure is here.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, despite the White House’s enthusiasm for another reconciliation bill, administration officials have not yet told lawmakers what policies they want considered, according to three people speaking on condition of anonymity.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Sens. Roger Wicker (R-Miss.) and Lindsey Graham (R-S.C.) — chairs of the committees on Armed Services and Budget, respectively — also said before leaving for recess they have not received guidance from the White House. Sen. Ted Cruz (R-Texas), chair of the Senate Commerce Committee, said he still hadn't heard from the administration about its broader set of legislative priorities heading into the fall.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;At this point, the loudest reconciliation push in the Senate is coming from deficit hawks like Sen. Ron Johnson, who wants to use another bill to cut spending further than what conservatives were able to achieve in the first package.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Leadership is telling us we’ll do one or two more reconciliations in this Congress,” the Wisconsin Republican told reporters earlier this summer. “So the clock’s ticking”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;While Senate Majority Leader John Thune has left the door open to doing a second reconciliation bill, he hasn’t provided a specific timeline for doing so.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;One of the three people waiting to hear from Trump said the push for another party-line package is coming not as much from the administration as from the House. There, Budget Chair Jodey Arrington (R-Texas) has said lawmakers should try to rework policies cut from the first reconciliation bill to comply with Senate rules. But there’s skepticism in the Senate that the House will be able to successfully relitigate those proposals.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“My sense is that there's more enthusiasm in the House than in the Senate, and that makes sense,” said Sen. Jerry Moran (R-Kan.). “They can do things with 51 votes anyway, most of what we have to do requires 60. And that means that senators, if you have a desire to actually legislate, need to find ways to legislate — and reconciliation is damaging to that relationship.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But House Republicans are also navigating their own slim margins and ideological divides. Conservatives and centrists clashed over cuts to Medicaid and clean energy tax credits in the “big, beautiful bill,” and lawmakers could have a diminished appetite for further battles over hot-button issues, especially heading into an election year.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Some House GOP aides were alarmed earlier this week when a hard-line think tank, the Economic Policy Innovation Center, pitched an extended moratorium on Medicaid funding for large abortion providers in a Republican Study Committee staff briefing.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;RSC leadership has stressed its megabill working group is designed at this point to generate ideas and put down markers, but EPIC’s recommendation could be a harbinger of other disputes to come.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Republicans are already struggling to sell voters on the first megabill back in their home states and districts, where town halls and other constituent events in the early weeks of recess have &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/06/gop-town-halls-anger-backlash-00494925" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;so far been rocky&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;One House Republican, granted anonymity to speak candidly, said there would be some “hesitancy” to dive back into reconciliation.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We did so much in the first,” the member said. “It's going to be harder to do a second one.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Benjamin Guggenheim contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>114</id>
            <title>Journalists kneel during the funeral ceremony of Victoria Roshchyna, 27, a Ukrainian journalist who reported on the Russian invasion of Ukraine and died in Russian captivity, in central Kyiv on Aug. 8, 2025.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/10/lindsey-graham-trump-putin-china-ukraine-00502584</link>
            <description>"What would a good deal look like? Making sure that 2022 doesn't happen again," he told NBC's Kristen Welker.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-10T15:14:55</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>7</id>
                <name>Gregory</name>
                <surname>Svirnovskiy</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\b7ff2fa9-4c2d-4200-9b75-70019426f20b.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;China is watching as President Donald Trump pushes for a diplomatic solution to Russian President Vladimir Putin's war in Ukraine, Sen. Lindsey Graham told NBC's Kristen Welker in an interview that aired Sunday. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The stakes?&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"If it ends in a way that looks like that Putin's overly rewarded, there goes Taiwan," Graham (R-S.C.) said on "Meet the Press."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump's latest gambit to end the war, now more than six months into his new term, will see him &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/08/trump-putin-meeting-00500815" target="_blank"&gt;meet with Putin in Alaska this Friday&lt;/a&gt;, the first time Russia's president will set foot in the U.S. in roughly a decade.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;It comes after Putin last week &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/08/trump-takes-putins-ceasefire-offer-to-europe-00500701" target="_blank"&gt;presented special envoy Steve Witkoff with a ceasefire offer&lt;/a&gt;, and Trump on Friday suggested "there’ll be some swapping of territories to the betterment of both" sides in peace talks.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Ukrainian President &lt;a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/zelenskyy-rejects-giving-up-land-to-end-war/" target="_blank"&gt;Volodymyr Zelenskyy on Saturday morning flatly rejected the idea&lt;/a&gt; that Kyiv might part with territory in negotiations to stop the fighting.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Graham, who told Welker he hopes "Zelenskyy can be part of the process," said other elements of peace talks will govern whether a deal makes sense for Ukraine and its partners.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"What would a good deal look like? Making sure that 2022 doesn't happen again," he told Welker, referencing the start of the current war. "On Biden's watch and Obama's watch, Russia invades. The goal for me, and I think President Trump, is to end it forever. Now, what would that look like? You'll have some land swaps, but only after you have security guarantees to Ukraine to prevent Russia from doing this again."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;China, a major purchaser of Russian oil, is on the president's mind, Graham said, just days after the White House announced that tariffs on India would be hiked to 50 percent for its own consumption of oil from Russia.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"I am here to tell you that President Trump will end this war in a way to prevent a third invasion and not to entice China to take Taiwan," Graham said. "We're not out to humiliate Putin, we're out to get a deal to make sure there's no third invasion."&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>115</id>
            <title>President Donald Trump participates in a trilateral signing ceremony with Armenian Prime Minister Nikol Pashinyan and Azerbaijan President Ilham Aliyev in the State Dining Room of the White House, Friday, Aug. 8, 2025, in Washington.</title>
            <link>ppeals-court-rules-trump-clamp-down-on-spending-data-defies-congress-authority-00501348</link>
            <description>An order issued Saturday evening by the D.C. Circuit Court of Appeals panel gives the administration until Friday to restore the data online.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-09T20:19:23</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>4</id>
                <name>Kyle</name>
                <surname>Cheney</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\a53acf74-6391-4df0-a22b-0ab71f42ea57.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;A federal appeals court panel &lt;a href="https://media.cadc.uscourts.gov/orders/docs/2025/08/25-5266LDSN.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;shot down&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a Trump administration bid to make secret a public database of federal spending that researchers say is crucial to ensure the administration is not flouting Congress’ power of the purse.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In an order issued Saturday evening, the three-judge D.C. Circuit Court of Appeals panel voted unanimously to give the administration until Friday to put the data back online.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Two of the three appeals judges assigned to the matter also signed onto a forceful opinion declaring that the administration’s bid to conceal the data was an affront to Congress’ authority over government spending, one that threatened the separation of powers and defied centuries of evidence that public disclosure is necessary for the public good.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“No court would allow a losing party to defy its judgment. No President would allow a usurper to command our armed forces,” Judge Karen Henderson, a George H.W. Bush appointee, wrote in support of the decision to deny the Trump administration’s request to keep the data under wraps while litigation over the issue goes forward. “And no Congress should be made to wait while the Executive intrudes on its plenary power over appropriations.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration ignited the legal battle when it decided in March to abruptly shut down the &lt;a href="https://apportionment-public.max.gov" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;database&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, claiming the widely available public data threatened the president’s ability to manage federal spending. Henderson noted that the decision came amid a torrent of lawsuits questioning whether the administration was preparing to illegally “impound” — or withhold — congressionally mandated spending required by law to disburse. The administration claimed the database also forced the disclosure of information meant to be shielded from public view.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;U.S. District Judge Emmet Sullivan rejected that view out of hand last month, in a lawsuit brought by Citizens for Responsibility and Ethics in Washington and the Protect Democracy group. The Clinton-appointed judge ordered the administration to immediately restore the website. The Justice Department quickly appealed and won a short-term pause of Sullivan’s decision. But Saturday’s ruling by the appeals court panel ends that pause.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Henderson agreed with Sullivan, saying Congress’ power is “at its zenith” when it comes to both approving federal spending and requiring details of that spending to be publicly disclosed. In other words, only Congress — not the administration — could decide to shut down the database.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Judge Robert Wilkins, an Obama appointee, joined Henderson’s 25-page opinion. The third judge on the panel, Biden appointee Bradley Garcia, voted with Henderson and Wilkins but did not join her opinion.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The ruling lands just as a simmering fight over Trump’s authority to dictate federal spending has been ramping up on Capitol Hill. Trump has long flirted with the notion that the president has the power to impound funds that he views cut against Executive Branch priorities, and courts have eyed warily his administration’s decision to mass-terminate federal grants and contracts representing billions of dollars in congressionally required spending. The Justice Department has argued that the funds for those terminated programs could be reissued in plenty of time to satisfy Congress’ requirements, but Trump budget officials have &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/20/pocket-rescissions-white-house-funding-trick-00410444" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;floated workarounds&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that have made some lawmakers uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The decision Saturday is not a final ruling on the underlying legal question about whether the administration is obliged to make the data public. But unless the full bench of the appeals court steps in or the administration gets relief from the Supreme Court, the ruling means the data is likely to be public within days. The panel agreed to give the administration until Aug. 15 to restore the database.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>116</id>
            <title>Pelosi (left), seen with House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries, led the push for national redistricting reform when she was speaker.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/08/redistricting-house-democrats-california-texas-00498773</link>
            <description>Former Speaker Nancy Pelosi, who pushed for national reforms, now says her party "cannot and will not unilaterally disarm."</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-08T03:45:00</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>14</id>
                <name>Nicholas</name>
                <surname>Wu</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\111e747f-a530-48a1-b148-2a8f24556c95.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;The last time House Democrats held the majority, they made a sweeping package of good-government reforms — including an attempt to end partisan gerrymandering — a centerpiece of their legislative agenda.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“The people should choose their politicians,” then-Speaker Nancy Pelosi &lt;a href="https://pelosi.house.gov/news/press-releases/floor-speech-on-the-for-the-people-act" target="_blank"&gt;said in 2021&lt;/a&gt;, moments before the House passed the bill that would later die in the Senate. “Politicians should not be choosing their voters.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Now, as President Donald Trump pushes Republicans in red states to redraw congressional district lines to their benefit, some Democrats are abandoning their past push for reforms. Instead, they're cheering on leaders like California Gov. Gavin Newsom who say their party must fight fire with fire.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Pelosi, in a statement to POLITICO, said she backs Newsom’s effort to overrule a bipartisan California map and counter GOP attempts to “rig the elections in their favor.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Her U-turn is emblematic of the larger rethinking underway within the Democratic Party, where leaders who once embraced anti-gerrymandering initiatives and feared a race to the bottom in partisan warfare between red and blue states are now increasingly willing to set aside their lofty goals — at least temporarily.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;It’s another facet of the dilemma that’s vexed Democrats since Trump first won the presidency. They’ve tried to present themselves to voters as “adults in the room” willing to set aside partisanship for the public good. But now that they’re being confronted with a potential existential threat to regaining power in 2026 or beyond, they’re entertaining bare-knuckle tactics.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;That includes some groups who have long advocated for high-minded changes to the political system, such as the National Democratic Redistricting Committee, a group founded in 2017 by former Attorney General Eric Holder.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“This organization is taking a posture that we're not going to oppose states taking corrective and temporary measures,” said its president, John Bisognano.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;And it’s happening in the House, too, where the reform agenda promoted under Pelosi has fallen by the wayside. While Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries and members of his leadership team continue to advocate for voting rights advancements and other key policies, they've not made them central to their opposition to Trump and his Republican allies in Congress.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Rep. Joe Morelle (D-N.Y.), the top Democrat on the committee overseeing federal elections, called Trump an “anomalous figure” requiring an emergency response — including when it comes to gerrymandering.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I will be an advocate for continuing to try to create national standards, but until those national standards are agreed to by everyone, I think it's going to make it increasingly difficult for states to continue to engage in a more nonpartisan system of redistricting,” he said in an interview. “As with so many things, Donald Trump shatters the norms and the standards that we have lived for, and as we try to improve our democracy, he is just shattering it. We have no choice but to respond in kind.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The rethinking has been prompted by Texas Republicans’ decision to respond to Trump’s push to launch an unusual mid-decade redrawing of congressional lines in a special legislative session called last month by GOP Gov. Greg Abbott. The effort is now on hiatus with Democratic state lawmakers having fled the state to deny Republicans a quorum in protest of what they see as a partisan power grab.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Other Republican-controlled states such as Missouri, Ohio and &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/07/vance-indiana-00497634" target="_blank"&gt;Indiana&lt;/a&gt; could follow Texas’ lead and rework their own congressional maps to shore up the three-seat House GOP majority ahead of next year’s midterm elections.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Confronted with claims of partisan overreach, Republicans gladly point to Democratic states that have drawn their own gerrymanders. Illinois’ 14-3 map in a state where Trump won 44 percent of the vote has been excoriated by good-government advocates. New York’s move to sidestep an independent map ended up in the courts and threw the 2022 midterms &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/05/16/new-york-house-map-chaos-00032931" target="_blank"&gt;into chaos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Democratic Rep. Mike Quigley, asked by a POLITICO reporter Thursday at an event in his hometown of Chicago, said he is "aware that our maps in Illinois are gerrymandered."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"Look, in an ideal world, these maps are drawn by nonpartisan commissions, and they represent what the Constitution said we should do," he said. "We're not there yet. ... So you can't be a Boy Scout in a situation like this — you have to be as tough as they are."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Enter Newsom, who has &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/04/california-fires-back-at-texas-redistricting-00493314" target="_blank"&gt;triggered the effort&lt;/a&gt; to expand Democrats’ advantage in California by overriding the map and sifting as many as five seats away from Republicans — which could entirely offset the Texas redraw.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The effort has rekindled the war over redistricting inside the Golden State, which has been done by an independent citizens commission since a successful 2010 ballot initiative. Before the vote, Pelosi and other prominent California Democrats — including then-Rep. Adam Schiff, then-state Sen. Alex Padilla, who are now both U.S. senators — &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/archives/blogs/politi-cal/story/2010-02-12/nancy-pelosi-congressional-democrats-weigh-in-on-redistricting-measure" target="_blank"&gt;opposed stripping line-drawing power&lt;/a&gt; from elected officials and backed a measure to maintain state lawmakers’ control.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Foes of independent California redistricting, like Pelosi, tried to persuade voters it wasted tax dollars on unaccountable bureaucrats. But their opponents countered that officeholders were motivated to protect their turf.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Elected officials don’t like to change the system that got them elected unless they can be super sure about what comes out of that and that they’re going to be okay,” said Eric McGhee, a Public Policy Institute of California expert who has written extensively about redistricting.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Only later did California’s most prominent Democrats embrace independent redistricting as a national matter. Now, they’re back on familiar ground, defending their party’s right to undertake its own power play in the face of GOP efforts elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“While we continue to support enacting legislation to create nationwide independent redistricting commissions, Democrats must respond to Republicans’ blatant partisan power grab,” Pelosi said in her statement. “Democrats cannot and will not unilaterally disarm.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Her fellow House Democrats don’t have any remorse about the political capital spent trying to pass the voting rights legislation in previous Congresses, though some are wistful about their failure in light of their current predicament.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Both their sweeping campaigns-and-elections package, dubbed the For the People Act, and a narrower measure aimed at restoring the 1965 Voting Rights Act, named after the late Rep. John Lewis, ran headlong into the Senate filibuster and now have zero path to passage under the GOP trifecta.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“This is an example of why we need it,” said Missouri Rep. Emanuel Cleaver, whose Kansas City–area district could be redrawn by the state GOP in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Quigley said that Democrats should continue "pushing and advocating" for national redistricting standards, "educating the public of where we can be and why it matters" — even as they pursue their own partisan lines.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Rep. Jamie Raskin of Maryland, the top Democrat on the Judiciary Committee, also argued for reviving Democrats’ voting bills in a future Congress and for eventually going even further by implementing multi-member congressional districts and ranked-choice voting.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But he acknowledged the reality of the situation Democrats face.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I would rather fight fire with water and put gerrymandering out of business,” he said. “But if the Republicans are going to plunge us into a race to the bottom, then we have to fight back with every means at our disposal.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Shia Kapos, Nicole Markus, Jeremy White and Liz Crampton contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>117</id>
            <title>“I have always conducted myself with integrity," Mills said in response to the latest personal allegations.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/06/cory-millis-threats-allegations-gop-00496518</link>
            <description>So long as national party operatives view the Florida lawmaker’s seat as safe, there is little incentive for GOP leaders to engage.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-06T17:46:07</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>10</id>
                <name>Hailey</name>
                <surname>Fuchs</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\dbee7265-0ea9-4ce6-ac07-8eb4a39ac034.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Rep. Cory Mills has recently faced accusations that he has &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/03/27/congress/ethics-committee-will-investigate-allegations-against-florida-republican-00254461" target="_blank"&gt;benefited from federal contracts&lt;/a&gt; while in office, that he &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/02/21/congress/cory-mills-police-assault-investigation-00205496" target="_blank"&gt;assaulted a onetime girlfriend&lt;/a&gt; in his Washington apartment and, just this week, that he &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/05/gop-rep-mills-accused-of-threatening-to-release-nude-videos-of-ex-girlfriend-00495059" target="_blank"&gt;threatened another ex&lt;/a&gt; with the release of nude videos.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;So far, the drumbeat of tawdry allegations has raised eyebrows in Washington, but it has not translated into any overt effort to sideline the two-term Florida Republican.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;GOP leaders in the House and in his home state appear to be betting that Mills’ various messes will sort themselves out without blowing back on the party more broadly — and potentially threatening its hold on power.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump won Mills’ district by 12 points last year, and Mills himself won reelection by a slightly higher margin. Because national party operatives view his seat as safe, there is little incentive for GOP leaders to engage as the accusations swirl. A spokesperson for Speaker Mike Johnson did not return a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Mills, 45, has denied wrongdoing in the contracting matter, which is now under a House Ethics Committee review, as well as the new claims of personal threats first made in a July police report and made public this week. The third incident was resolved after the ex-girlfriend who initially told police in February that Mills had assaulted her &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/02/24/congress/cory-mills-denies-assault-allegations-00205873" target="_blank"&gt;withdrew the allegation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In a statement Tuesday, Mills said the latest accusation was a “political attack” concocted by a political rival, “all to score political headlines.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“These claims are false and misrepresent the nature of my interaction,” he said. “I have always conducted myself with integrity, both personally and in service to Florida’s 7th District.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;While Republican leaders appear poised to give Mills space, plenty of others see a potential political mess in the making — starting with House Democrats, whose campaign arm recently put his seat on their list of “Districts in Play” for the midterms despite the bearish 2024 results. At least three Democrats have already announced they plan to challenge him.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Floridians deserve leaders who protect people, not threaten them,” said Noah Widmann, one of the three. “Cory Mills is unfit to serve.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Among House Republicans, quiet concerns have been brewing for months about whether Mills’ behavior could give Democrats a real opening. Some of his GOP colleagues are wondering if they should start looking for another candidate to back in the district, according to three Republicans granted anonymity to describe private talks.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“What if he is arrested for real?” said one of the three, a member.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Another House Republican, also granted anonymity to discuss the sensitive matter, said other controversies — including an &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/dc-md-va/2025/07/15/cory-mills-gop-congressman-rent-lawsuit-eviction/" target="_blank"&gt;allegation of unpaid rent&lt;/a&gt; that Mills dismissed last month as a misunderstanding with building management — have also surprised lawmakers.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;A recent NOTUS report &lt;a href="https://www.notus.org/congress/cory-mills-iraq-bronze-star" target="_blank"&gt;questioned&lt;/a&gt; whether Mills has been honest about his military service for which he was awarded a Bronze Star; Mills acknowledged “different recollections during chaotic wartime events” but said he was entitled to the honor. And as House Ethics probes his businesses’ contracts, which concern the sales of weapons or other equipment, Mills continues to sit on the House Foreign Affairs and Armed Services committees.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“And then this whole other issue is disturbing,” the lawmaker said about the new accusations of personal threats.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Those are rooted in Mills’ relationship with Lindsey Langston, the 2024 Miss United States. She told authorities last month that Mills contacted her multiple times threatening to release nude images and videos of them having sex and harm her future romantic partners after she broke off the relationship earlier this year, according to a police report obtained this week by POLITICO. The report said Langston shared messages with Mills backing up her claims.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Columbia County, Florida, sheriff’s department forwarded the report to the state Department of Law Enforcement for investigation. The agency confirmed Wednesday it received the request but declined to comment further.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Langston’s allegations have been complicated by the involvement of Anthony Sabatini, a hard-right former Florida legislator who ran against Mills in 2022 and is now serving as Langston’s lawyer.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Mills suggested this week that Sabatini was engaged in a political vendetta, but the attorney said Wednesday that he no longer lives in Mills’ district and has no plans to seek his seat. The evidence of Mills’ actions speaks for itself, he said.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Sabatini said he plans to take Langston’s allegations directly to the House Ethics Committee, which he said has “the independent authority to investigate this on its face.” A spokesperson for the panel declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“If they don’t do it, it’s only because [of] the margins,” he said.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, in Florida, conversation has surrounded just what Mills’ future in GOP politics might look like. One top Republican operative in the state said, even before the latest reports, Mills had been “extremely frustrated” in the House and “there are people out thinking about running for the congressional seat” if he does not run for a third term.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“He didn’t know if he wanted to continue in Congress,” said the operative, who was granted anonymity to discuss the sensitive matter.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Mills first won his seat in 2022 after post-Census redistricting created new GOP-friendly lines for the 7th District, stretching from Orlando’s north suburbs to the Atlantic coast — prompting Democratic Rep. Stephanie Murphy to retire.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;His campaigns in both 2022 and 2024 were run with the aid of James Blair, a GOP consultant who now works as a deputy chief of staff for Trump and plays a key role in pushing the president’s agenda on the Hill.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, Mills was talking openly about running for the Senate seat that was vacated by Marco Rubio when he resigned to become secretary of State. But Republican Gov. Ron DeSantis appointed Florida Attorney General Ashley Moody instead, and Trump likely snuffed out any chance of a successful primary challenge by &lt;a href="https://www.nrsc.org/uncategorized/president-trump-endorses-ashley-moody-for-u-s-senate-2025-07-28/" target="_blank"&gt;endorsing her late last month&lt;/a&gt; for next year’s special election.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In his statement, Mills said he would “remain focused on serving my constituents and advancing America First policies” and had no plans to comment further on Langston’s allegations.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“My team and I will fully cooperate to ensure the truth is made clear,” he said.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mia McCarthy contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>118</id>
            <title>Rep. Mike Flood, seen on stage, was greeted with chants of "Vote him out!" at his Lincoln, Nebraska, town hall Monday.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/06/gop-town-halls-anger-backlash-00494925</link>
            <description>The explosive events could reflect broad backlash to GOP governance. Or they might be just another outgrowth of political polarization.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-06T03:45:00</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>14</id>
                <name>Nicholas</name>
                <surname>Wu</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\f3649366-2cbc-4875-bb05-9764ac44d9fa.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Republicans went home for the summer with a plan to sell President Donald Trump’s “big, beautiful bill” to their constituents. Some are starting to find that voters aren’t buying it.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In the latest display of backlash, audience members jeered Nebraska Rep. Mike Flood at a Monday town hall, shouting “Liar!” and “You don’t care about us!” over the two-term lawmaker as he made the case for the megabill, which Trump signed into law last month. By the end, chants of “Vote him out!” threatened to drown out his closing comments.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Such scenes of angry constituents confronting lawmakers are nothing new. They were commonplace in 2009 as Democrats pressed forward with a health care overhaul and in 2017 when Republicans sought to undo it.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;This time around, there is a fierce debate underway about whether the town hall explosions are part of a genuine backlash to GOP governance in Washington — one that could presage another wave election as seen in 2010 and 2018 — or just another reflection of America’s political polarization.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Many Republicans are dismissing the outbursts, concluding they have been choreographed by Democrats and groups aligned with them and do not reflect genuine voter sentiment. Some — including Trump — have claimed without evidence that paid protesters are responsible.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I think Democrats have been organized to actually act out in town halls, and I think if you’re going to have a town hall where you’re inviting people to come in with the intent of protesting, that’s what you’re going to get,” Sen. Mike Rounds (R-S.D.) said Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But left-of-center activists say the GOP dismisses voters’ outrage at their peril. Groups might be helping to publicize and organize protests around lawmakers’ events, they say, but that is merely harnessing a real grass-roots backlash to what Republicans are pursuing in Washington.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I would say the level of energy and grassroots anger at Congress is at a higher level of intensity now than it was in 2017, and I think that's evidenced by just the numbers that you're seeing on the ground,” said Ezra Levin, the co-executive director of Indivisible,a progressive organization that came to prominence organizing protests that year.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Evaluating the competing claims has grown more complicated because Republican lawmakers, on the whole, have been doing fewer events in the classic town hall format — in-person, with an open attendance policy.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With the GOP megabill still in its initial stages earlier this year, the chair of the House GOP’s national campaign committee explicitly urged members &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/03/04/congress/gop-town-halls-richard-hudson-00210024" target="_blank"&gt;not to hold in-person town halls&lt;/a&gt; during congressional breaks. But recently, with the legislation now signed into law, the party committee urged members to get out and &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/07/29/nrcc-recess-memo-00480758" target="_blank"&gt;sell the bill’s benefits&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Even then, some Republicans say they plan to shy away from the type of town hall that Flood held on Monday — open mic, on a college campus in a relatively liberal corner of his district.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Rep. Aaron Bean of Florida, who represents a solid Republican district, said he has a busy recess schedule speaking to small GOP and civic groups. But he said he is passing on scheduling the larger public forums.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Only people who have never supported me want me to do a town hall,” he said.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Bean insisted he wasn’t insulating himself from criticism — he said he’s fielded plenty of skeptical questions on tariffs from constituents who work in affected industries. But he said the only negative feedback he has heard on the megabill is "from left wing lunatics” who “want a place to protest.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Rounds said he prefers to hold smaller “coffees” as opposed to a “free for all.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I make it very clear: One, it’s going to be organized, and two, if you want to shut the coffee down, just act out and we’ll just shut it down for everybody else,” he said. “On the other hand, if you want to ask straightforward questions or hard questions, that’s fine, but we’re going to act like adults.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;National Democrats, however, argue that Republicans who are opting for more controlled events are shirking their responsibilities as public officials — and obscuring the popular backlash to the GOP’s domestic agenda.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Town halls are about more than just politics, they're about good governing, which Republicans clearly don’t care about,” said DCCC spokesperson Viet Shelton, who added that the recent outbursts are “made-for-TV, viral examples of how unpopular and politically toxic” the megabill is for Republicans.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump administration officials remain confident that the megabill’s benefits will more than offset any costs felt by voters, especially those in GOP strongholds like Flood’s Nebraska district. They ascribe the angry questioning and heckling to partisan plants and say Republican lawmakers just need to keep on the attack&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"All it is is a Democrat op," said one senior Trump adviser granted anonymity to discuss the backlash. The person added that Trump and congressional Republicans' approval ratings versus those of Democrats have the White House feeling bullish on the party's chances in the midterms.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Recent polling does in fact show the Democratic Party with &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/elections/democratic-party-poll-voter-confidence-july-2025-9db38021?gaa_at=eafs&amp;amp;gaa_n=ASWzDAj8cXRuo32XZC6ozTTRnwbnXHh4njnbuhAADT8EX8Af1PF0dvh4pn15roUN-zI%3D&amp;amp;gaa_ts=68927ca9&amp;amp;gaa_sig=vmTG1Kjj9z96zDBZ0Os8MZNbLPQxABWdth0bns4Ujfjwgz_zyAqd7cF-KQjTfdINrbgr_f8PtNAEj8lmqFoJYw%3D%3D" target="_blank"&gt;rock-bottom approval ratings&lt;/a&gt;, though it remains to be seen if that will translate into GOP votes. Democrats hold a narrow lead in the RealClearPolitics polling average for the &lt;a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/state-of-the-union/generic-congressional-vote" target="_blank"&gt;generic congressional ballot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;NRCC spokesperson Mike Marinella similarly said that GOP town halls were “being hijacked into choreographed Democrat theater packed with left-wing activists” and said the “manufactured outrage exposes just how desperate Democrats are to distract from their toxic agenda and failing candidates.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Audience members weren't screened ahead of Flood’s event, according to Taylor Gage, a spokesperson for the lawmaker. Flood has no plans to abandon the town hall format, Gage added, but Monday’s was the third of three such events he usually hosts each year.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Nebraska Democratic Party publicized attendance details for Flood’s event on its &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/NebraskaDemocraticParty/posts/pfbid0a6sFzcYKZveHKZhnjpJyKjLGcdiy3jGAEaugwrVpdrxkJhZFyCvPHQq6r2txN2bml?__cft__[0]=AZX27bf31lJADaz28d0MvaeNbZ9LKukClIegtRLUVifTDPmR9sbI5voKCtqkCdAxHKWorio3XQKGd9lTv32X1ReHntMx7GsvMisEblWOg_1RCJTeJ_PqQGgvgC0eBTZeDe3nGB0kBpUKjhpqg1Un0vbT6rrnn64_lyfMKLJIj1Z72I1E1aXKjZisVG2dsnaNK_E&amp;amp;__tn__=%2CO%2CP-R" target="_blank"&gt;social media channels&lt;/a&gt;. Before the event Monday, it posted, “Voters of #NE01, you know what to do!“&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But Chair Jane Kleeb said Republicans were indulging in “conspiracy theories” by suggesting that attendees were paid or protested out of anything other than their own genuine outage and are otherwise “out of touch with how deeply their cruel cuts are angering the public.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Democrats have sought to weaponize GOP members’ reticence to hold town halls. Local progressive groups have organized events to go on “with or without” their GOP representatives’ participation, and some congressional Democrats &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/07/24/congress/dems-hit-the-road-00475644" target="_blank"&gt;are undertaking summer tours&lt;/a&gt; of Republican districts.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;One such member, Rep. Yassamin Ansari of Arizona, said she planned on “bringing their stories with me back to D.C. — even if their own representatives won't."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But the volatile politics of town halls can swing both ways. Several House Democrats have faced their own backlash at events earlier this year from voters angry about the Gaza War and what they have seen as weak pushback against Trump. The same night as Flood’s town hall, three people were arrested at a Renton, Wash., event held by Democratic Rep. Adam Smith, &lt;a href="https://www.kiro7.com/news/local/three-arrested-during-disruption-rep-adam-smith-town-hall/53LBRI4N7RD5HFF552K26XMBTA/" target="_blank"&gt;according to local news reports&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I don't know if Congress knows what's coming for them,” Levin said. “I would say that applies to Republicans because they are backing up Trump. It also applies to Democrats who are refusing to fight back and are headed into a primary season.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Jordain Carney, Lisa Kashinsky and Jake Traylor contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;CORRECTION: An earlier version of this story misspelled the name of Flood spokesperson Taylor Gage.</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>119</id>
            <title>Rep. Cory Mills during the 2024 Conservative Political Action Conference in Fort Washington, Maryland, Feb. 23, 2024.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/05/gop-rep-mills-accused-of-threatening-to-release-nude-videos-of-ex-girlfriend-00495059</link>
            <description>Lindsey Langston, winner of the 2024 Miss United States contest, filed a police report in Florida. Mills denied wrongdoing.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-05T22:21:17</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>19</id>
                <name>Aaron</name>
                <surname>Pellish</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\5bc9111a-9fd5-4648-a70c-a5cb461dc02a.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;A woman who said she had been in a relationship with Rep. Cory Mills has accused the Republican member of Congress from Florida of threatening to release nude videos of her after she broke off their relationship, according to a police report.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Lindsey Langston, a Florida Republican state committee member and 2024 winner of the Miss United States beauty pageant, told authorities on July 14 that Mills also threatened to harm any of her future romantic partners, according to a report she made to the Columbia County Sheriff’s Department that was obtained Tuesday by POLITICO.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Her allegations were sent to the Florida Department of Law Enforcement for review, said Steven Khachigan, a spokesperson for the sheriff's department. The FDLE did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Mills, who has represented a district south of Daytona Beach since 2023, has not been charged and told POLITICO in a statement that he was unaware of the police report.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We have not been made aware of any report or allegations from law enforcement or the alleged complainant,” Mills said. “These claims are false and misrepresent the nature of my interactions. I have always conducted myself with integrity, both personally and in service to Florida’s 7th District.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The incident was first reported Tuesday by Blaze Media and Drop Site News.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Langston told the sheriff’s department that she was in a relationship with Mills from November 2021 until February, when she said she ended it after seeing media reports &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/cory-mills-investigation-florida-fd64fe6bee97de24b993545c70a03361" target="_blank"&gt;that police in Washington were called to&lt;/a&gt; investigate an alleged assault by the representative against a woman.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Both &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/02/24/congress/cory-mills-denies-assault-allegations-00205873" target="_blank"&gt;Mills and the woman denied&lt;/a&gt; that any assault took place, and Mills was not charged in the incident.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Langston said that Mills told her he was separated from his wife at the time they started their relationship. The representative is still married.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;She told police that after she broke up with him, Mills contacted her multiple times threatening to release nude images and videos of them having sex, according to the report, which said she provided law enforcement with messages that allegedly backed up her claims.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Anthony Sabatini, Langston’s attorney and a Lake County, Florida commissioner who challenged Mills for Congress in 2022, said Langston also filed a restraining order against Mills. POLITICO has not independently confirmed the restraining order.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In a statement, Mills told POLITICO he believes Sabatini is “weaponizing the legal system to launch a political attack.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>120</id>
            <title>Oversight Chair James Comer (R-Ky.) announced that he was summoning nearly a dozen former officials to appear for depositions on the Epstein investigation.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/05/epstein-subpoenas-department-of-justice-00494129</link>
            <description>The House Oversight Committee chair was required to send the subpoenas after a Democratic-led subcommittee vote in July.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-05T11:41:20</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>13</id>
                <name>Giselle</name>
                <surname>Ruhiyyih</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\769fbd2a-02a2-474d-aa7c-683d510bdf1a.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;The House Oversight Committee on Tuesday issued subpoenas for Department of Justice records on the Jeffrey Epstein investigation, as well as for interviews with a slate of former government officials in connection to the case.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Oversight Chair James Comer (R-Ky.) &lt;a href="https://oversight.house.gov/release/chairman-comer-subpoenas-bill-and-hillary-clinton-former-u-s-attorneys-general-and-fbi-directors-and-records-related-to-jeffrey-epstein/" target="_blank"&gt;announced that he was summoning&lt;/a&gt; nearly a dozen former officials to appear for depositions on the Epstein investigation — a list that includes former President Bill Clinton and former Secretary of State Hillary Clinton.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Former U.S. Attorneys General William Barr, Alberto Gonzales, Jeff Sessions, Loretta Lynch, Eric Holder and Merrick Garland, as well as former FBI Directors Robert Mueller and James Comey were also tapped to give testimony in connection to the case.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Comer was required to send the subpoenas after &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/07/23/congress/house-panel-votes-to-subpoena-epstein-files-00472015" target="_blank"&gt;a Democratic-led subcommittee vote&lt;/a&gt; in July.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The move is the latest in a broader battle over the Epstein files, which took the Trump administration by storm last month as anger boiled over from within MAGA circles about the administration’s handling of the case.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The committee’s subpoena of Bill Clinton in particular seems more symbolic than substantive. No former president has ever testified to Congress under the compulsion of a subpoena — and lawmakers have tried only twice before: once in 1953, when the House Un-American Activities Committee subpoenaed Harry Truman, and once in 2022, when the Jan. 6 select committee subpoenaed Donald Trump.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Neither president testified in those instances, and the Justice Department has long cited Truman’s example — though not backed by any legal precedent — to suggest that it is improper for Congress to compel even former presidents to testify, given separation of powers concerns.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;While the president has tried to brush off the growing outcry — and &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/07/17/trump-epstein-wall-street-journal-00461787" target="_blank"&gt;lashed out at The Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt; over its report of a letter he allegedly wrote to the disgraced financier for his birthday, which he denies authoring — Republicans have split over their approach to the issue.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump has publicly raged about the case, suggesting it was a Democratic plant to undermine him. He’s also sought to mollify his angry base, directing Attorney General Pam Bondi to seek the release of grand jury documents amid outrage from within his own MAGA sphere, although it is not clear if there would be &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/07/18/jeffrey-epstein-grand-jury-documents-case-00464189" target="_blank"&gt;anything revelatory in those documents&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Deputy Attorney General Todd Blanche &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/newsletters/politico-nightly/2025/07/25/why-is-doj-speaking-with-ghislaine-maxwell-00434342" target="_blank"&gt;also met with Epstein co-conspirator&lt;/a&gt; and convicted sex offender Ghislaine Maxwell last month amid the heightened public pressure.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Maxwell, who is serving a 20-year prison sentence for child sex trafficking and other crimes, was moved to a minimum-security federal prison camp in Texas just days after her meetings with Blanche — a transfer that came as &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/07/28/trump-ghislaine-maxwell-pardon-jeffrey-epstein-00479862" target="_blank"&gt;Trump has made clear&lt;/a&gt; that a pardon for the convicted sex offender is within his purview.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Kyle Cheney contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>121</id>
            <title>Attorney General Pam Bondi, followed by Federal Bureau of Investigation Director Kash Patel and U.S. Attorney for the District of Columbia Jeanine Pirro arrive for a press briefing in the James S. Brady Press Briefing Room at the White House on Aug. 11, 2025.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/28/bondi-patel-to-testify-before-congress-amid-epstein-fallout-00534353</link>
            <description>The attorney general and FBI director are expected to face fierce questioning by Democrats and some Republicans over the DOJ’s handling of the Jeffrey Epstein case.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-08-28T13:07:22</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>46</id>
                <name>Will</name>
                <surname>Smith</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\15a7188c-50f9-428f-8391-a532a081123a.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Two top Justice Department officials are expected to testify before the House Judiciary Committee in the coming weeks amid fallout over the administration's handling of the Jeffrey Epstein case, according to two people granted anonymity to share scheduling information not yet public.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;FBI director Kash Patel is set to give testimony Sept. 17, with attorney general Pam Bondi on tap to appear Oct. 9. Both have been invited as part of the Judiciary Committee’s general oversight work, and each will have an opportunity to outline some of the pieces of a crime bill President Donald Trump wants Hill Republicans to produce in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But the hearings will likely focus most heavily on how the DOJ has maneuvered around the release of files related to the late, convicted sex offender.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Senior Republicans have continued over the August recess to press the Trump administration to unseal more Epstein documents after a mutiny over their release caused chaos in the GOP-controlled House, running the chamber aground before lawmakers left town early in late July.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;DOJ started transmitting some of the so-called Epstein files last week in compliance with a subpoena from the House Oversight and Government Reform Committee. And Alex Acosta, President Donald Trump’s former labor secretary who singed off on Epstein’s previous plea deal as a then-U.S. attorney in Florida, will separately sit for a transcribed interview with the Oversight panel Sept. 19.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;However, lawmakers otherwise have so far received scant new information during the month-long district work period, with members of both parties promising to continue to press the issue when the House is set to return to session next week.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Bondi has, in particular, &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/07/24/pam-bondi-jeffrey-epstein-files-00475897" target="_blank"&gt;been the subject&lt;/a&gt; of Republican consternation over allegedly withholding documents she at one point promised to reveal.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
    </articles>
</articlearchive>
